<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-GB" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:/government/announcements</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/announcements.atom"/>
  <title>Announcements on GOV.UK</title>
  <author>
    <name>HM Government</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2016-11-23T19:54:51+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/345015</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T19:54:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T19:54:51+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-23-november-2016"/>
    <title>Press release: PM meeting with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg: 23 November 2016</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Prime Minister Theresa May hosted NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg at Downing Street for a wide-ranging discussion on security issues.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Downing Street spokesperson said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister hosted NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg at Downing Street this afternoon for a wide-ranging discussion on security issues.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister reaffirmed the UK’s unwavering support for NATO and said we will remain a cornerstone of the Alliance. Secretary General Stoltenberg agreed that the UK is playing a leading role by meeting our commitment to spend 2 per cent of GDP on defence, contributing troops to deterrence measures in Eastern Europe and maintaining our independent nuclear deterrent.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister and Secretary General Stoltenberg spoke about the importance of NATO members meeting the 2 per cent commitment and agreed to continue to encourage allies to increase defence spending.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;They discussed the recent US election and the importance of the transatlantic bond to security. Secretary General Stoltenberg relayed his recent conversation with President-elect Trump, in which they had agreed on the enduring importance of NATO.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister and Secretary General Stoltenberg agreed that any EU defence proposals should be about strengthening structures within NATO rather than duplicating existing structures.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Finally they discussed the importance of adapting to emerging threats and the way in which the UK could contribute to increasing cyber capabilities among NATO allies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/345013</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T19:53:14+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T19:53:14+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/defence-secretary-reviews-natos-reassurance-role-with-secretary-general"/>
    <title>News story: Defence Secretary reviews NATO’s reassurance role with Secretary General</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Defence Secretary Sir Michael Fallon has discussed how NATO can further reassure allies and partners in Europe during talks with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in London.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a working dinner at Lancaster House with the Secretary General this evening Sir Michael praised the NATO’s Enhanced Forward Presence commitment in the Baltic States in the face of an increasingly assertive and unpredictable Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also agreed to build on the commitments made at the Warsaw and Wales Summits: countering hybrid threats, supporting greater maritime co-operation and boasting our cyber security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defence Secretary Sir Michael Fallon said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Britain is stepping up to deal with the threats we face.  The Army and RAF are providing assurance to NATO allies; with troops going to Estonia and Poland and jets being deployed to the Black Sea.  Our Royal Navy is taking on people traffickers and training new Libyan forces in the Mediterranean.  The UK is ahead of the NATO spending target and we’re ensuring the Royal Navy is growing with cutting-edge new aircraft carriers, frigates and submarines launching over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the NATO Defence Ministerial in Brussels last month the Sir Michael said that the UK will commit RAF Typhoon aircraft to Romania as part of the NATO Southern Air Policing mission to offer reassurance to Black Sea allies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He confirmed that the UK will send 800 personnel to Estonia as one of four framework battalions to NATO’s Enhanced Forward Presence, to which France and Denmark will contribute further troops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week at the Foreign Affairs Council (Defence), the Defence Secretary called on European partners to do more and increase their defence spending to the NATO 2% commitment, meaning they are better positioned to tackle the new and emerging threats to European security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backed by a £178 billion equipment plan and defence budget rising in real terms for the rest of this parliament, the UK is one of the five of the 28 countries in NATO that meets the 2% spending target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344734</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:28:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/autumn-statement-2016-philip-hammonds-speech"/>
    <title>Statement to Parliament: Autumn Statement 2016: Philip Hammond's speech</title>
    <category label="Statement to Parliament" term="Statement to Parliament"/>
    <summary>The Autumn Statement speech in full.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated:&lt;/em&gt; Updated with video&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="https://youtu.be/G7L2DCrGD5I"&gt;Autumn Statement 2016: Chancellor’s statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a privilege to report today on an economy which the IMF predicts will be the fastest growing major advanced economy in the world this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An economy with employment at a record high – and unemployment at an 11 year low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An economy which, through the hard work of the British people, has bounced back from the depths of  recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And an economy which has confounded commentators at home and abroad with its strength and its resilience since the British people decided, exactly five months ago today, to leave the European Union and chart a new future for our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That decision will change the course of Britain’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has thrown into sharp relief the fundamental strengths of the British economy that will ensure our future success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global reach of our services industries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strength of our science and high-tech manufacturing base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the cutting-edge British businesses that are leading the world in disruptive technologies,
But it’s a decision that also makes more urgent than ever the need to tackle our economy’s long-term weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the productivity gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The housing challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the damaging imbalance in economic growth and prosperity across our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We resolve today to confront those challenges head on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prepare our country to seize the opportunities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in doing so, to build an economy that works for everyone…and where every corner of this United Kingdom is part of our national success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to pay tribute to my predecessor, my Rt Hon Friend the Member for Tatton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My style will, of course, be different from his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that I will prove no more adept at pulling rabbits from hats than my successor as Foreign Secretary has been at retrieving balls from the back of scrums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my focus on building Britain’s long-term future will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took over an economy with the highest budget deficit in our postwar history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And brought it down by two-thirds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But times have moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And our task now is to prepare our economy to be resilient as we exit the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And match-fit for the transition that will follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will maintain our commitment to fiscal discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While recognising the need for investment to drive productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And fiscal headroom to support the economy through the transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me turn now to the forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2010, the Office for Budget Responsibility has provided an independent economic and fiscal forecast, to which the government must respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I thank Robert Chote and his team for their hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s OBR forecast is for growth to be 2.1% in 2016; higher than forecast in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 the OBR forecasts growth to slow to 1.4%, which they attribute to lower investment and weaker consumer demand, driven, respectively, by greater uncertainty and by higher inflation resulting from sterling depreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s slower, of course, than we would wish, but still equivalent to the IMF’s forecast for Germany, and higher than the forecast for growth in many of our European neighbours, including France and Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the effects of uncertainty diminish, the OBR forecasts growth recovering to 1.7% in 2018, 2.1% in 2019 and 2020, and 2% in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the OBR is clear that it cannot predict the deal the UK will strike with the EU, its current view is that the referendum decision means that potential growth over the forecast period is 2.4 percentage points lower than would otherwise have been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OBR acknowledges that there is a higher degree of uncertainty around these forecasts than usual.
Despite slower growth, the UK labour market is forecast to remain robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve delivered over 2.7 million new jobs since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This forecast shows that number growing in every year – another 500,000 over the OBR forecast – providing security for working people across the length and breadth of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, employment grew fastest in the North East; the claimant count fell fastest in Northern Ireland; pay grew most strongly in the West Midlands; and every UK nation and region saw a record number of people in work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A labour market recovery that is working for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monetary policy has played an important role in supporting growth since the Referendum decision. 
But a credible fiscal policy remains essential for maintaining market confidence and restoring the economy to long term health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In view of the uncertainty facing the economy, and in the face of slower growth forecasts, we no longer seek to deliver a surplus in 2019-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Prime Minister and I remain firmly committed to seeing the public finances return to balance as soon as practicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While leaving enough flexibility to support the economy in the near-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am publishing a new draft Charter for Budget Responsibility, with three fiscal rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the public finances should be returned to balance as early as possible in the next Parliament, and, in the interim, cyclically-adjusted borrowing should be below 2% by the end of this Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, that public sector net debt as a share of GDP must be falling by the end of this Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And third, that welfare spending must be within a cap, set by the government and monitored by the OBR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of an effective framework, the welfare bill in our country spiralled out of control, with spending on working-age benefits trebling in real terms between 1980 and 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the action we’ve taken since 2010, that spending has now stabilised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cap I am announcing today takes into account policy changes since the last Budget, setting a realistic baseline reflecting all announced welfare policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I confirm again that the government has no plans to introduce further welfare savings measures in this parliament beyond those already announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now turn Mr Speaker, to the OBR’s fiscal forecasts, but first I will set out the key drivers of changes since the Budget:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-Budget changes to welfare and housing policies cost the Exchequer £8.6 billion over the forecast period;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expected ONS classification changes have added £12 billion since Budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And tax receipts have been lower than expected this year, causing the OBR to revise down projected revenues in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added to this is a structural effect of rapidly rising incorporation and self-employment, which further erodes revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining these pressures with the impact of forecast weaker growth, and taking account of the measures I shall announce today, the OBR now forecast that in cash terms, borrowing is set to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£68.2 billion this year; falling to £59 billion next year; £46.5 billion in 2018-19; then £21.9 billion; £20.7 billion, and finally £17.2 billion in 2021-22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall public sector net borrowing as a percentage of GDP will fall from 4% last year to 3.5% this year, and will continue to fall over the Parliament, reaching 0.7% in 2021-22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the lowest deficit as a share of GDP in two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OBR expects cyclically adjusted public sector net borrowing to be 0.8% of GDP in 2020-21, comfortably meeting our target to reduce it to less than 2% …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And leaving significant flexibility to respond to any headwinds the economy may encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OBR’s forecast of higher borrowing and slower asset sales, together with the temporary effect of the Bank of England’s action to stimulate growth, translates into an increased forecast for debt in the near-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OBR forecasts that debt will rise from 84.2% of GDP last year to 87.3% this year, peaking at 90.2% in 2017-18 as the Bank of England’s monetary policy interventions approach their full effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018-19, debt is projected to fall to 89.7% of national income - the first fall in the national debt as a share of GDP since 2001-02.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is forecast to continue falling thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stripping out the effects of the Bank of England interventions, underlying debt peaks this year at 82.4% of GDP and falls thereafter to 77.7% by 2021-22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have received representations from a range of external bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of them calling for fiscal expansion; while others have suggested there is no need at all to respond to a changed economic outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reflects the challenge we face of resolving how best to protect the recovery, build on the economy’s strengths, yet at the same time respond appropriately to the warnings of a more difficult period ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with our debt forecast to peak at 90% next year, and a deficit this year of 3.5%, I have reached my own 
judgement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a judgement based on a sober analysis of our fiscal position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also on a realistic appraisal of the weakness of UK productivity, and the urgent need to address our fiscal challenge from both ends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing to control public expenditure, but also growing the potential of the economy and protecting the tax base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we choose in this Autumn Statement to prioritise additional high-value investment, specifically in infrastructure and innovation, that will directly contribute to raising Britain’s productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the key judgement we make today is that our hard-won credibility on public spending means we can fund this commitment, in the short-term, from additional borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While funding all other new policies announced in this Autumn Statement through additional tax and spending measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the responsible way to secure our economy for the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The productivity gap is well known, but shocking nonetheless:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lag the US and Germany by some 30 percentage points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we also lag France by over 20 and Italy by 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means in the real world, it takes a German worker 4 days to produce what we make in 5; which means, in turn, that too many British workers work longer hours for lower pay than their counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That has to change if we are to build an economy that works for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raising productivity is essential for the high-wage, high-skill economy that will deliver higher living standards for working people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can announce today a new National Productivity Investment Fund of £23 billion to be spent on innovation and infrastructure over the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investing today for the economy of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me set out for the House how this money will be used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, we do not invest enough in research, development and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the pace of technology advances and competition from the rest of the world increases, we must build on our strengths in science and tech innovation to ensure the next generation of discoveries is made, developed and produced in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today I can confirm the additional investment in R&amp;amp;D, rising to an extra £2 billion per year by 20-21, announced by my Right Honourable Friend, the Prime Minister on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, economically productive infrastructure directly benefits businesses.
But families, too, rely on roads, rail, telecoms – and, especially housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have made good progress, with the number of new homes being built last year hitting an eight-year high. 
But for too many, the goal of home ownership remains out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October, my Right Honourable Friend, the Communities Secretary launched the £3 billion Home Builders’ Fund, to unlock over 200,000 homes and up to £2 billion to accelerate construction on public sector land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we must go further still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of delivering the housing we so desperately need in the places where it is currently least affordable is not a new one…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the effect of unaffordable housing on our nation’s productivity makes it an urgent one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Right Honourable Friend, the Communities Secretary will bring forward a Housing White Paper in due course, addressing these long-term challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the meantime, we can take further steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest objections to housing development is often the impact on local infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will focus government infrastructure investment to unlock land for housing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new £2.3 billion Housing Infrastructure Fund to deliver infrastructure for up to 100,000 new homes in areas of high demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, to provide affordable housing that supports a wide range of need, we will invest a further £1.4 billion to deliver 40,000 additional affordable homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will relax restrictions on government grant to allow a wider range of housing-types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also announce a large-scale regional pilot of Right to Buy for Housing Association tenants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And continued support for home ownership through the Help to Buy: Equity Loan scheme and the Help to Buy ISA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, this package means that over the course of this Parliament, the government expects to more than double, in real terms, annual capital spending on housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coupled with our resolve to tackle the long term challenges of land supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This commitment to housing delivery represents a step-change in our ambition to increase the supply of homes for sale and for rent, to deliver a housing market that works for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, reliable transport networks are essential to growth and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this Autumn Statement commits significant additional funding to help keep Britain moving now, and to invest in the transport networks and vehicles of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will commit an additional £1.1 billion of investment in English local transport networks, where small investments can offer big wins;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£220 million to address traffic pinch points on strategic roads;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£450 million to trial digital signalling on our railways to achieve a step-change in reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And squeeze more capacity out of our existing rail infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, £390 million to build on our competitive advantage in low emission vehicles and the development of connected autonomous vehicles; plus a 100% first year capital allowance for the installation of electric vehicle charging infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department for Transport will continue to work with Transport for the North to develop detailed options for Northern Powerhouse Rail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Right Honourable Friend, the Transport Secretary will set out more details of specific projects and priorities over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our future transport, business and lifestyle needs will require world class digital infrastructure to underpin them. 
So my ambition is for the UK to be a world leader in 5G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means a full-fibre network; a step-change in speed, security and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will invest over £1 billion in our digital infrastructure to catalyse private investment in fibre networks and to support 5G trials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from April we will introduce 100% business rates relief for a 5 year period on new fibre infrastructure, supporting further roll out of fibre to homes and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have chosen to borrow to kick-start a transformation in infrastructure and innovation investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we must sustain this effort over the long term if we are to make a lasting difference to the UK’s productivity performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today I have written to the National Infrastructure Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ask them to make their recommendations on the future infrastructure needs of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the assumption that government will invest between 1% and 1.2% of GDP every year from 2020 in economic infrastructure covered by the Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put this in context, we’ll spend around 0.8% of GDP on the same definition this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also backing the Commission’s interim recommendations on the Oxford-Cambridge growth corridor published last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With £110m of funding for East West Rail, and a commitment to deliver the new Oxford to Cambridge Expressway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this project can be more than just a transport link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can become a transformational tech-corridor, drawing on the world-class research strengths of our two best-known universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I welcome the Commission’s continuing work on delivery model options, and we will carefully consider its final recommendations in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major increase in infrastructure spending I’ve announced today will represent a significant increase in funding through the Barnet formula of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over £250 million to the Northern Ireland Executive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£400 million to the Welsh government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And £800 million to the Scottish government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But public investment is only part of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About half of our economic infrastructure is financed by the private sector, and we will continue to support that investment through the UK Guarantees Scheme, which I am today extending until at least 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new capital investment I have announced today will provide the financial backbone for the government’s Industrial Strategy, which the Prime Minister spoke about on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A firm foundation upon which my Rt Hon Friend the Business Secretary will work with industry to build our ambition of an economy that works for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can announce four further measures to back business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am doubling UK Export Finance capacity to make it easier for British businesses to export;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am funding Charlie Mayfield’s business-led initiative to boost management skills across British businesses; and 
I am taking a first step to tackle the longstanding problem of our fastest growing technology firms being snapped up by bigger companies, rather than growing to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By injecting an additional £400m into venture capital funds through the British Business Bank, unlocking £1 billion of new finance for growing firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am launching a Treasury-led review of the barriers to accessing patient capital in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This government recognises that for too long, economic growth in our country has been too concentrated in London and the south east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not just a social problem, it’s an economic problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London is one of the highest-productivity cities in the world and we should celebrate that fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no other major developed economy has such a gap between the productivity of its capital city and its 2nd and 3rd cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we must drive up the performance of our regional cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we publish our strategy for addressing productivity barriers in the Northern Powerhouse; and give the go ahead today to a programme of major roads schemes in the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Midlands Engine strategy will follow shortly, but I am today providing funding for the evaluation study for the Midlands Rail hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are investing in local infrastructure in every region of England:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can announce the allocation of £1.8 billion from the Local Growth Fund to the English regions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£556 million to Local Enterprise Partnerships in the North of England, £542 million to the Midlands and East of England, and £683 million to LEPs in the South West, South East and London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will announce the detailed breakdown of allocations to individual LEPs shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devolution remains at the heart of this government’s approach to supporting local growth, and we recommit today to our City deals with Swansea, Edinburgh, North Wales and Tay Cities – and I can announce today we’re beginning negotiations on a city deal for Stirling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that every city in Scotland will be on course to have a City Deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support new mayoral combined authorities in England, I can announce that we will grant them new borrowing powers to reflect their new responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we continue discussions with London and the West Midlands on possible devolution of further powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can announce today that London will receive £3.15 billion as its share of national affordable housing funding to deliver over 90,000 homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that we are devolving to London the adult education budget, and giving London greater control over the delivery of employment support services for the hardest to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, I have deliberately avoided making this statement into a long list of individual projects being supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am going to make one exception:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will act today, with just seven days to spare, to save one of the UK’s most important historic houses: Wentworth Woodhouse near Rotherham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said to be the inspiration for Pemberley in Jane Austen’s Pride and Prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wentworth Woodhouse is now at critical risk of being lost to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A local effort has secured millions in funding – subject to the balance required being found by November 30th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will provide a £7.6 million grant towards urgent repairs to safeguard this key piece of Northern heritage. I can also confirm distribution of a further £102 million of LIBOR bank fines to Armed Forces and Emergency Services charities…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…including £20 million to support the Defence and National Rehabilitation Centre at Stanford Hall in Nottinghamshire – and £3 million from the Tampon Tax Fund for Comic Relief to distribute to a range of women’s charities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose to invest in our economic infrastructure because it can transform the growth potential of our economy, as well as improving the quality of people’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That investment is only possible because the government is prepared to take the tough decisions to maintain control of current spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, public spending was 45% of GDP – this year it’s set to be 40%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since 2010 we’ve seen crime fall by more than a quarter;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest proportion ever of good or outstanding schools;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of doctors has increased by 10,000;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pensioner poverty at its lowest level ever;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lowest ever number of children being raised in workless households;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the highest ever number of young people going on to study full time at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have demonstrated beyond doubt that controlling public spending is compatible with world-class public services and social improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as the OBR’s debt projections demonstrate, we have more work to do to eliminate the deficit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So departmental spending plans set out in the Spending Review last autumn will remain in place, and departmental expenditure in 21-22 will grow in line with inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The £3.5 billion of savings to be delivered through the Efficiency Review announced at the Budget, and led by my Right Honourable Friend, the Chief Secretary, must be delivered in full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, however, exceptionally agreed to provide additional funding to the Ministry of Justice to tackle urgent prison safety issues increasing the number of prison officers by 2,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having run two large spending departments in previous roles, I came to this job with some very clear views about the relationship between the Treasury and spending departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want departments to be incentivised to drive efficiencies. And I want the Treasury to be an enabler for good, effective spending across government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kickstart this new approach, I will allow up to £1bn of the savings found by the efficiency review in 19/20 to be reinvested in priority areas and I have budgeted today accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, we manage public spending so that we can invest in the public’s priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the government has underlined those priorities with a series of commitments and protections for the duration of this Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can confirm that, despite the fiscal pressures, we will meet our commitments to protect the budgets of key public services and defence;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will keep our promise to the world’s poorest through our overseas aid budget,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will meet our pledge to our country’s pensioners through the triple lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we look ahead to the next Parliament, we will need to ensure we tackle the challenges of rising longevity and fiscal sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the government will review public spending priorities and other commitments for the next Parliament in light of the evolving fiscal position at the next Spending Review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker I now turn to taxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2010 the government has put a business-led recovery at the heart of our plan, we’ve cut corporation tax from 28% to 20%, sending the message that Britain is open for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The additional investment in productivity and infrastructure that I have announced underscores that message….
And the raft of investments in the UK announced since the referendum – by Softbank, Glaxo, Nissan, Google and Apple amongst others, confirms it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My priority as Chancellor is to ensure that Britain remains the number one destination for business – creating the investment, the jobs and the prosperity to protect our long-term future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how much business values certainty and stability, and so I confirm today that we will stick to the business tax roadmap we set out in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporation tax will fall to 17%, by far the lowest overall rate of corporate tax in the G20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will deliver the commitments we have made to the oil and gas sector;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the Carbon Price Support will continue to be capped out to 2020;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we will implement the business rates reduction package worth £6.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can confirm today that having consulted further, my Right Honourable Friend, the Communities Secretary will lower the transitional relief cap from 45% next year to 43%, and from 50% to 32% the year after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I will also increase the Rural Rate Relief to 100%, giving small businesses in rural areas a tax break worth up to £2,900 per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In return for our competitive rates, the tax base must be sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April 2017 we will align the employee and employer National Insurance thresholds at £157 per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be no cost to employees, and the maximum cost to business will be an annual £7.18 per employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance premium tax in this country is lower than in many other European countries, and half the rate of VAT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to raise revenue, which is required to fund spending commitments I am making today, it will rise from 10% currently, to 12% from next June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time I can confirm the government’s commitment to legislate next year to end the compensation culture surrounding whiplash claims – a major area of insurance fraud – saving drivers an average of £40 on their annual premiums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, technological progress is changing the way people live, and the way they work;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tax system needs to keep pace. For example, the OBR has today highlighted the growing cost to the Exchequer of incorporation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the government will consider how we can ensure that the taxation of different ways of working is fair between different individuals, and sustains the tax-base as the economy undergoes rapid change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will consult in due course on any proposed changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, the government will take action now to reduce the difference between the treatment of cash earnings and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of employees pay tax on a cash salary. But some are able to sacrifice salary and pay much lower tax on benefits in kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unfair, and so from April 2017 employers and employees who use these schemes will pay the same taxes as everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following consultation with stakeholders, ultra-low emission cars, pensions saving, childcare and the cycle to work scheme will be excluded from this change. And certain long-term arrangements will be protected until April 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For pensions that have been drawn-down, I will also reduce to £4,000 the Money Purchase Annual Allowance, to prevent inappropriate double tax relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is committed to tackling tax evasion, avoidance and aggressive tax planning, and the UK tax gap is now one of the lowest in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we must constantly be alert to new threats to our tax base – and be willing to move swiftly to counter them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Budget we committed to removing the tax benefits of disguised earnings for employees, and I am now going to do the same for the self-employed and employers, raising a further £630 million over the forecast period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will shut down inappropriate use of the VAT flat rate scheme that was put in place to help small businesses;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will abolish the tax advantages linked to Employee Shareholder Status in response to evidence it is primarily being used for tax-planning purposes by high-earning individuals;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will introduce a new penalty for those who enable the use of a tax avoidance scheme that HMRC later challenges and defeats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These measures – and others set out in the Autumn Statement document – raise around £2 billion over the forecast period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, there is understandable public concern that the pitch is tilted in favour of large multinational groups which are able to use cross-border structures to manage their tax liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following detailed consultation, I can confirm that we will implement our new restriction on tax relief for corporate interest expenses, and reform the way that relief is provided for historic losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These measures, scored at Budget 2016, will help to ensure large businesses will always pay tax in years where they make substantial profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will also mean that businesses cannot avoid tax by borrowing excessively in the UK to fund their overseas activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They take effect in April, and raise over £5 billion from the largest businesses in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, I said that the tax system must be fair and that means rewarding those who work hard by helping them to keep more of what they earn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one tax reform the government has pursued since 2010 to improve the lot of working people.
Raising the tax-free personal allowance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we entered government in 2010 it was £6,475.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after 6 years it is £11,000, and will rise to £11,500 in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, we have more than halved the tax bill of someone with a salary of £15,000 to just £800.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a massive boost to the incomes of low and middle earners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2010 we’ve cut income tax for 28 million people and taken 4 million people out of income tax altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can confirm today that, despite the challenging fiscal forecasts, we will deliver on our commitment to raising the allowance to £12,500, and the higher rate threshold to £50,000, by the end of this Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once £12,500 has been reached, the personal allowance will rise automatically during the 2020s in line with inflation, rather than the National Minimum Wage as currently planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be for the Chancellor to decide from year to year whether more is affordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as taking millions of ordinary people out of tax, the government introduced the National Living Wage and gave a pay rise to over a million workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has also introduced 15 hours a week of free childcare for all 3 and 4 year olds, and we will double that for working families from September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s education reforms have raised standards and expanded opportunity with 1.4 million more children now in ‘good’ or ‘outstanding’ schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the new capital funding I have provided today for grammar schools will help to continue that trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, Mr Speaker, has pledged to invest in our NHS and we are delivering on that promise: backing the NHS’ Five Year Forward View plan for the future with £10 billion of additional funding a year by the end of 2020-21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we recognise that more needs to be done to help families make ends meet and to ensure every household has opportunities to prosper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I can announce the National Living Wage will increase from £7.20 to £7.50 in April next year. 
That’s a pay rise worth over £500 a year to a full-time worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating jobs, lowering taxes and raising wages addresses directly the concerns of ordinary families.
And the revenue-raising measures I have announced today enable me to go further to help families on low wages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Universal Credit is an important reform to our benefits system and is designed to make sure work always pays. 
We want to reinforce that position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April, we can reduce the Universal Credit taper rate from 65% to 63%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is effectively a targeted tax cut worth £700m in 21-22 for those in work on low incomes;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will increase the incentive to work and encourage progression in work;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will help 3 million households across our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that a market economy is the best way of delivering sustained prosperity for the British people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will always support a market led approach; but we will not be afraid to intervene where there is evidence of market failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will look carefully over the coming months at the functioning of key markets, including the retail energy market, to make sure they are functioning fairly for all consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the private rental market, letting agents are currently able to charge unregulated fees to tenants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have seen these fees spiral, often to hundreds of pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is wrong. Landlords appoint letting agents and landlords should meet their fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I can announce today that we will ban fees to tenants as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will consult on how best to ban pensions cold calling and a wider range of pension scams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also help those who rely on income from modest savings to get by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low interest rates have helped our economy recover, but they’ve significantly reduced the interest people can earn on their cash savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we will launch a new, market-leading savings bond through NS&amp;amp;I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detail will be announced at the Budget, but we expect our new Investment Bond will have an interest rate of around 2.2% gross and a term of 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Savers will be able to deposit up to £3,000, and we expect around 2 million people to benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The announcements I have made today lower taxes on working people; boost wages; back savers; and bear down on bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early 2017, we will begin the roll out of tax-free childcare across Britain, providing a saving of up to £2,000 per child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once it’s rolled-out, we will keep it under review to ensure it’s delivering the support they need to working families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one further area of household expenditure where the government can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The oil price has risen by over 60% since January; and sterling has declined by 15% against the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means significant pressure on prices at the pump here in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today we stand on the side of the millions of hardworking people in our country by cancelling the fuel duty rise for the seventh successive year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total this saves the average car driver £130 a year and the average van driver £350.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tax cut worth £850 million next year, and means the current fuel duty freeze is the longest for 40 years.
Mr Speaker, I have one further announcement to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first Autumn Statement as Chancellor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After careful consideration, and detailed discussion with the Prime Minister, I have decided that it will also be my last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker I am abolishing the Autumn Statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other major economy makes hundreds of tax changes twice a year, and neither should we.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the spring Budget in a few months will be the final spring Budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting in autumn 2017, Britain will have an autumn Budget, announcing tax changes well in advance of the start of the tax year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2018 there will be a Spring Statement, responding to the forecast from the OBR, but no major fiscal event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If unexpected changes in the economy require it, then I will, of course, announce actions at the Spring Statement, but I won’t make significant changes twice a year just for the sake of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change will also allow for greater Parliamentary scrutiny of Budget measures ahead of their implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, this is a long-overdue reform to our tax-policy making process and brings the UK into line with best practice recommended by the IMF, IFS, Institute for government and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OBR report today confirms the underlying strength and resilience of the British economy….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Autumn Statement responds to the challenge of building on that strength, while also heeding the warnings in the OBR’s figures, as we begin writing this new chapter in our country’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It re-states our commitment to living within our means;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it sets out our choice to invest in our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sends a clear message to the world that Britain is open for business;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it provides help to those who need it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Mr Speaker, we have made our choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have set our course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a great nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bold in our vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confident in our strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And determined in our ambition to build a country that works for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I commend this Statement to the House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/345007</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:50:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:50:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/the-minister-for-defence-procurement-has-announced-the-start-of-the-defence-industrial-policy-refresh-consultation"/>
    <title>News story: The Minister for Defence Procurement has announced the start of the Defence Industrial Policy Refresh consultation</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Minister for Defence Procurement has today launched a consultation on refreshing Defence Industrial Policy. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement was made at a Defence Growth Partnership Ministerial meeting which was attended by a number of key defence suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting was co-chaired by Jesse Norman, Parliamentary Under Secretary of State at the Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS) and Allan Cook Chairman of Atkins. This work is being led by the MOD but is closely aligned with the work on the National Industrial Strategy which BEIS are leading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the Strategic Defence and Security Review 2015 (SDSR15), the Government committed to develop a refreshed defence industrial policy. This will make clear that competition remains our preferred approach, delivering value for money and incentivising an innovative and productive industrial base. It will outline the further action we will take to help the UK’s defence and security industries, in particular Small and Medium Sized Enterprises (SMEs), to grow and compete successfully. The development of this policy is an important contribution to the new National Security Objective to promote our prosperity and is closely linked with other work in the MOD to promote innovation, exports and skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister for Defence Procurement, Harriett Baldwin said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am delighted to be able to formally launch the consultation on refreshing Defence Industrial Policy Refresh. This is a milestone in meeting our SDSR15 commitment and presents a unique opportunity for our defence industry, academics and non-traditional defence suppliers to make a valuable contribution to the continuing development of our Industrial Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I therefore call upon all our stakeholders, particularly SMEs, to engage in the consultation over the next 6 weeks to help us to refine our policy to not only deliver the best equipment for defence at the best value for the tax payer, but to support an innovative, prosperous and internationally competitive defence industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allan Cook, Industry co-chair of the DGP said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As co-chair of the Defence Growth Partnership - which seeks to develop the UK defence capabilities and increase defence export sales - I welcome today’s launch of the industry consultation on the refresh of defence industrial policy. I would encourage industry of all sizes, non-traditional suppliers and academia to participate in the consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The refresh is an opportunity to help to deliver a vibrant, competitive and successful defence sector in the UK, contributing to the needs of our Armed Forces, allies and partners around the world as well as making a significant contribution to the UK’s prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MOD is keen to use this opportunity to reach out to all the members of our defence industry, from large defence suppliers to the smallest SME, and are interested to hear the views of non-traditional suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to make it easier for businesses to work with defence and make defence business more attractive to a wider range of suppliers, which is why this external consultation is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultation will run from 22nd November 2016 to January 6th 2017 and can be accessed &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/defence-industrial-policy"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344986</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tobias-ellwood-statement-on-plans-to-demolish-bedouin-village-in-israel"/>
    <title>News story: Tobias Ellwood statement on plans to demolish Bedouin village in Israel</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Minister for the Middle East comments on plans to demolish a Bedouin village in southern Israel.  </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue was also discussed during Foreign Office oral questions in the House of Commons on Tuesday 22 November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias Ellwood said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have raised with the Israeli Ambassador the concerns expressed in the House of Commons about plans to demolish the Bedouin village of Umm al-Hiran in the Negev.  Demolition orders delivered to residents had stated that initial demolitions would occur on 22 November. Although the demolition did not happen yesterday, the threat remains.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The UK calls on the Israeli authorities and Bedouin community to work together to find a solution that meets the needs and respects the rights of the people affected. This should include a robust planning process that adequately consults and addresses the needs of Israel’s Bedouin communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow Foreign Office Minister Tobias Ellwood on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/Tobias_Ellwood"&gt;@Tobias_Ellwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.instagram.com/ukforeignoffice/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ukforeignoffice"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/foreign-and-commonwealth-office?trk=biz-companies-cym"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="contact " id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344986</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tobias-ellwood-statement-on-plans-to-demolish-bedouin-village-in-israel"/>
    <title>News story: Tobias Ellwood statement on plans to demolish Bedouin village in Israel</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Minister for the Middle East comments on plans to demolish a Bedouin village in southern Israel.  </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue was also discussed during Foreign Office oral questions in the House of Commons on Tuesday 22 November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias Ellwood said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have raised with the Israeli Ambassador the concerns expressed in the House of Commons about plans to demolish the Bedouin village of Umm al-Hiran in the Negev.  Demolition orders delivered to residents had stated that initial demolitions would occur on 22 November. Although the demolition did not happen yesterday, the threat remains.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The UK calls on the Israeli authorities and Bedouin community to work together to find a solution that meets the needs and respects the rights of the people affected. This should include a robust planning process that adequately consults and addresses the needs of Israel’s Bedouin communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow Foreign Office Minister Tobias Ellwood on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/Tobias_Ellwood"&gt;@Tobias_Ellwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.instagram.com/ukforeignoffice/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ukforeignoffice"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/foreign-and-commonwealth-office?trk=biz-companies-cym"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="contact " id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344986</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tobias-ellwood-statement-on-plans-to-demolish-bedouin-village-in-israel"/>
    <title>News story: Tobias Ellwood statement on plans to demolish Bedouin village in Israel</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Minister for the Middle East comments on plans to demolish a Bedouin village in southern Israel.  </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue was also discussed during Foreign Office oral questions in the House of Commons on Tuesday 22 November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias Ellwood said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have raised with the Israeli Ambassador the concerns expressed in the House of Commons about plans to demolish the Bedouin village of Umm al-Hiran in the Negev.  Demolition orders delivered to residents had stated that initial demolitions would occur on 22 November. Although the demolition did not happen yesterday, the threat remains.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The UK calls on the Israeli authorities and Bedouin community to work together to find a solution that meets the needs and respects the rights of the people affected. This should include a robust planning process that adequately consults and addresses the needs of Israel’s Bedouin communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow Foreign Office Minister Tobias Ellwood on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/Tobias_Ellwood"&gt;@Tobias_Ellwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.instagram.com/ukforeignoffice/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ukforeignoffice"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/foreign-and-commonwealth-office?trk=biz-companies-cym"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="contact " id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/345002</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:31:44+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:31:44+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/civil-news-revised-checklists-to-help-avoid-claims-being-rejected"/>
    <title>News story: Civil news: revised checklists to help avoid claims being rejected</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>You can avoid common errors by using our checklists before billing for controlled work civil escape cases.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updated checklists are now available to help you ensure you receive payments as quickly as possible when billing for escape case work in these categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;civil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mental health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;immigration and asylum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These checklists are used by caseworkers to check your claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they are also useful for providers to help you ensure you have made the necessary checks and enclosed the required documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-are-the-changes"&gt;What are the changes?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The checklists have been revised to put more focus on the most common errors and how these can be avoided. But there is no change to our requirements when submitting bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="staged-checking-process"&gt;Staged checking process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new format sets out clearly the ‘stage 1’ and ‘stage 2’ checking process followed by our caseworkers. This in line with our approach for civil certificated billing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘stage 1’ checks itemise the issues that cause the highest number of rejects in each category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a caseworker sees a reason to reject under ‘stage 1’ then the claim is returned without further checks being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where a reason to reject is found under ‘stage 2’ the claim will be checked for a further 5 minutes or until 2 more reject reasons are found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-to-use-the-checklists"&gt;How to use the checklists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend that the checklists are used as a pre-submission check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your claim is rejected, you can use the checklist again to help ensure that there will be no further rejects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/escape-fee-case-claim-forms"&gt;EC-Claim 1: escape fee case claim form&lt;/a&gt; – to download updated checklists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344989</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T16:11:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T16:11:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/permitted-to-explore"/>
    <title>Press release: Permitted to explore</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>This permit will cover the management of extractive mining waste for the Land at Tinker Lane, Retford Road, between Blyth and Barnby Moor.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency has today (23 November) granted the environmental permit to allow Island Gas Limited (IGas) to carry out the drilling of an exploratory borehole at a site at Tinker Lane in Nottinghamshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision follows a rigorous assessment of the IGas proposals and detailed consideration of all comments submitted during two rounds of public consultations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The permit set out the conditions that IGas must follow in order to protect groundwater, surface water and air quality and to ensure the safe storage, management and disposal of waste materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IGas are planning to drill an exploratory borehole to explore the potential for gas production. They would like to drill a single vertical well down through the coal and shale layers to collect the rock samples for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should IGas receive the appropriate planning permission and begin the permitted activities, we will stringently enforce the conditions of the permit to ensure that waste is managed properly and local groundwater is protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The below link takes you to the published permit and decision document:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dn22-8pa-dart-energy-east-england-limited-environmental-permit-issued"&gt;Permit decision document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For media enquiries please contact our press office on 0115 8463781
Out of hours please call 0800 917 9264 and ask for the duty press officer
&lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.environment-agency.gov.uk"&gt;https://www.environment-agency.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt; Follow us on Twitter @EnvAgencyMids&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes for Editors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The application was submitted under the name of Dart Energy, the legal entity that holds the licence for PEDL 200. Dart Energy are wholly owned by Island Gas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344960</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T15:21:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T15:21:03+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/apprenticeship-support-and-knowledge-for-schools-project-launches"/>
    <title>News story: Apprenticeship support and knowledge for schools project launches</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>We have launched a project to raise the awareness and prestige of quality apprenticeships in schools. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The apprenticeship support and knowledge for schools (ASK) project will deliver apprenticeship and traineeship information to young people in years 10, 11, 12 and 13. This will ensure young people are aware of all the options available to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is funded by the Skills Funding Agency and National Apprenticeship Service and will offer young people in the North, Midlands, London and the South the skills they need to get on in work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will work with teachers, careers advisers, parents and governors, alongside other key partners, to support schools and ensure that they meet their statutory duties regarding the provision of impartial Information Advice and Guidance (IAG), specifically in relation to apprenticeships and traineeships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A core part of the ASK project includes identifying and recruiting 1,000 Apprenticeship Champions in schools across England to support the promotion of apprenticeships in their local areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skills and Apprenticeships Minister Robert Halfon said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I am committed to transforming this country into an apprenticeship nation. Initiatives like ASK and the 1,000 Apprenticeship Champions are essential to spreading the message that quality apprenticeships are a ladder of opportunity for all ages and all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This network of teachers and careers advisers will positively promote apprenticeships in a variety of ways to inspire students, teachers, parents and governors, whilst actively encouraging students of all abilities to consider apprenticeships as a viable and successful route into a career. Apprenticeship Champions will also create opportunities for students to engage with employers and apprentice ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="attachment_1828855" class="attachment-inline"&gt;
  &lt;a href="/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/571995/ASK_project_summary_for_stakeholders_and_partners.pdf"&gt;Apprenticeship support and knowledge for schools project summary for stakeholders and partners&lt;/a&gt;
  (&lt;span class="type"&gt;&lt;abbr title="Portable Document Format"&gt;PDF&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="file-size"&gt;419KB&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="page-length"&gt;2 pages&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information on how to book free support in your area can be found by visiting the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://amazingapprenticeships.com/request-support"&gt;amazing apprenticeships website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344980</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T15:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T15:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/national-infrastructure-commission-autumn-statement-response-government-acceptance-of-nic-recommendations-most-welcome-armitt"/>
    <title>Press release: National Infrastructure Commission Autumn Statement Response: Government acceptance of NIC recommendations most welcome - Armitt</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Deputy Chair of the National Infrastructure Commission responds to announcements made in the Autumn Statement</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Autumn Statement, Wednesday 23 November 2016, saw the Chancellor announce that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The government accepts the NIC’s recommendations to fund the next phase of East West Rail and the Oxford-Cambridge Expressway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The next NIC study will focus on how emerging technologies can improve infrastructure productivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The government has set the NIC’s fiscal remit between 1% and 1.2% of GDP each year from 2020 to 2050.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responding to the Autumn Statement, Deputy Chair of the National Infrastructure Commission, Sir John Armitt, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The government’s acceptance of the National Infrastructure Commission’s recommendations for the Cambridge, Milton Keynes, Oxford corridor is most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The growth corridor between Cambridge Milton Keynes and Oxford could help fire the British economy, but only if we back it with the homes and infrastructure it needs to thrive. Last week the NIC presented the compelling case for investment in East West rail and the Oxford Cambridge Expressway, as part of a wider joined up plan to help this region succeed. This is a once in a generation opportunity and the government is absolutely right to accept those recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the launch of the National Infrastructure Commission’s Technology study he said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From electric vehicles to the Internet of Things and artificial intelligence‎, the technologies of the future could have an enormous impact on the UK’s economic infrastructure and the ways in which rely upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;As new technologies develop, Britain must do everything it can to ensure that we are best placed to reap the benefits - and that includes incorporating innovative new systems and practices into the infrastructure that keeps our country moving.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Britain should seek to lead the world in harnessing the emerging technologies that can make our lives easier and our economy more productive. This study will consider  how we make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the announcement of the NIC’s fiscal remit he added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Today’s announcement represents a crucial step in the formation of the NIC. Providing a clear remit and a long-term funding guideline for British infrastructure will help this country plan for the long term and deliver the systems and networks we need to compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-cambridge--milton-keynes--oxford-corridor"&gt;The Cambridge – Milton Keynes – Oxford corridor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In relation to East West Rail and the Oxford-Cambridge Expressway, the NIC recommended that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommendation 4: The government should commit to delivering the Western Section of the East West Rail project before 2024 (the end of the rail industry’s Control Period 6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To achieve this, the government should bring forward £100m in funding to accelerate design and development, and commit construction monies as necessary to: avoid abortive cost (subject to the development process demonstrating rigorous disciplines in planning, cost management and value management); and integrate construction of the East West Rail Western Section with work on HS2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To fully maximise the benefits of the project local authorities should recognise the potentially transformational benefits of East West Rail and develop and agree, working with national government, an ambitious strategy for housing development and delivery around stations and station towns.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Commission will support this process as part of the second phase of the Cambridge-Milton Keynes-Oxford study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommendation 5: The government should commit up to £10m in development funding to continue work on the Central Section of the East West Rail link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government should provide clear guidance that a core objective for the development of this scheme should be to support the provision of new housing and connect it to local and regional labour markets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local partners and national government should work together to develop a plan for the Central Section which links development work on the East West Rail Central Section to options for local housing development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government should explore the potential for alternative delivery and financing mechanisms for the railway. This should include consideration of how third party contributions could be leveraged.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Commission will support this process as part of the second phase of the Cambridge-Milton Keynes-Oxford study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommendation 6: The government should commit £27m to the end of 2018/19 to fund the next phase of development work on the Oxford-Cambridge Expressway study, allowing the detailed design process to begin as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highways England should work with relevant local authorities to develop and assess the potential Expressway options and develop a proposal which maximises the scheme’s potential to unlock housing growth and connect it to local and regional labour markets, alongside delivering wider benefits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Commission will support this process as part of the second phase of the Cambridge-Milton Keynes-Oxford study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full interim report can be found &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-east-west-transport-links-could-provide-a-once-in-a-generation-opportunity-for-britains-silicon-valley-armitt"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="text-from-the-autumn-statement"&gt;Text from the Autumn Statement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The section of the Autumn Statement relating to the National Infrastructure Commission can be found &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/autumn-statement-2016-documents/autumn-statement-2016"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It is reproduced in full below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.5 National Infrastructure Commission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economic infrastructure (transport, energy, flood defences, water, waste, and digital communications) is crucial for the economy and for people’s daily lives. The government has put infrastructure at the heart of its economic strategy and has set up the National Infrastructure Commission (NIC) to provide expert advice on the country’s strategic infrastructure needs and independent recommendations on how to meet them. At Spending Review 2015, the government announced it would increase transport spending by 50% to invest £61 billion in this Parliament. Including the additional investment provided by the NPIF, annual central government investment in economic infrastructure will increase by almost 60% from £14 billion in 2016-17 to £22 billion in 2020-21.13&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government’s long-term investment decisions will be informed by the NIC to ensure they are targeted at the UK’s most critical infrastructure needs. To ensure the NIC’s recommendations are affordable, the government has set the NIC a fiscal remit. Government investment in the areas the NIC covers will rise to over 1% of GDP by 2020-21. The fiscal remit invites the NIC to set out recommendations on the assumption that spending on infrastructure will lie between 1% and 1.2% of GDP each year from 2020 to 2050. This would mark a sustained, long-term increase in infrastructure investment. The government will take all final spending decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIC study on Cambridge-Milton Keynes-Oxford corridor – The government welcomes the NIC’s interim report into the Cambridge-Milton Keynes-Oxford growth corridor, accepts the recommendation for an Oxford-Cambridge expressway,14 and will provide £27 million in development funding. The government will also bring forward £100 million to accelerate construction of the East-West Rail line western section and allocate £10 million in development funding for the central rail section. The government welcomes the NIC’s work looking at a range of delivery models for housing and transport in the corridor, including development corporations, and will carefully consider its final recommendations. Following a successful public call for ideas, the government has also asked the NIC to undertake a new study on how emerging technologies can improve infrastructure productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344943</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T14:22:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T14:22:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/1-million-reconstruction-project-to-solve-a590-lindal-dip-flooding"/>
    <title>Press release: £1 million reconstruction project to solve A590 Lindal ‘dip’ flooding</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>A £1 million project to resolve a long-running issue with flooding along the A590 at Lindal-in-Furness in Cumbria.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A £1 million Highways England project to resolve a long-running issue with flooding along the A590 at Lindal-in-Furness in Cumbria, is to get underway on Friday (25 November).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A section of the route, known locally as Lindal dip – at the junction with Green Lane east of the village - frequently floods in heavy rain. During last December’s storms temporary traffic lights had to be deployed several times to help drivers pass the flooded carriageway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;
  &lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="A590 flooding img" src="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/58533/Dip1.JPG"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A section of the A590 near Lindal will be raised and realiged to prevent flooding&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flooding is caused by a combination of factors including the carriageway dip and water from several sources, including the local road network, collecting on the A590.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work, which is due to be completed by the end of March, involves raising and realigning the carriageway and adding to &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-drainage-to-help-tackle-lindal-dip-flooding"&gt;major drainage improvements&lt;/a&gt; completed this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highways England project manager Peter Gee said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We know that local people and other road users will be delighted that work to resolve this long-running problem will get underway this month.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The drainage work and particularly the reconstruction of the carriageway, will lead to some disruption to drivers’ journeys over the next few months. We ask road users to bear with us while we deliver these improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key elements of the construction work include moving the carriageway 7 metres north west of the existing alignment and raising it by up to almost 2 metres in places.  An innovative ‘infiltration’ system will also be constructed – using a 1.2 metre diameter drainage pipe to help store rain water before slowly releasing it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several phases of traffic management will be needed and the schedule – which is weather dependent – currently includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;temporary traffic lights around the clock from 8pm on Friday until 8pm on Tuesday (29 November), and again from 8pm on Friday 2 December until 8pm on Tuesday 6 December&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a week of 8pm to 6am overnight work using temporary traffic lights from Tuesday 6 December until Monday 12 December&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 full overnight closures of the carriageway in both directions between 8pm and 6am on Monday 12 December and Tuesday 13 December&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-way traffic using narrow lanes and a 30 mph speed limit between Thursday 15 December and Wednesday 8 February&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;temporary traffic lights from Wednesday 8 February and Tuesday 14 March&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 final 8pm to 6am overnight full carriageway closures on Tuesday 14 March and Wednesday 15 March&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highways England and Cumbria County Council are working together to minimise disruption to road users’ journeys by coordinating the works at Lindal and a county council project in Ulverston to improve the junction with the A590 at Quebec Street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="general-enquiries"&gt;General enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public should contact the Highways England customer contact centre on 0300 123 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="media-enquiries"&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists should contact the Highways England press office on 0844 693 1448 and use the menu to speak to the most appropriate press officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344843</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T14:12:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T14:12:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/low-pay-commission-welcomes-acceptance-of-new-minimum-wage-rates"/>
    <title>Press release: Low Pay Commission welcomes acceptance of new minimum wage rates</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>National Living Wage and National Minimum Wage rates to increase.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Low Pay Commission (&lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt;), the body that advises the Government on the level of the minimum wage, today welcomed the acceptance of its recommendations for the rates to apply from April 2017. These include a 4.2 per cent increase in the National Living Wage (&lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt;), the rate for workers aged 25 and over, from £7.20 to £7.50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt; Chair Sir David Norgrove said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The &lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt; is required to make recommendations on the pace of increase in the National Living Wage such that it reaches 60 per cent of typical earnings by 2020, subject to sustained economic growth. The key challenge this year has been uncertainty in relation to the economic outlook following the decision to leave the EU, and whether we needed to go more slowly than our previous intention of straight line increases in the relative value of the rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The 4.2 per cent increase keeps the National Living Wage on course for the 2020 goal. The recommendation was a finely balanced decision. On the one hand, it is a significant increase at a time of average pay growth of around 2 per cent and should help protect low-paid workers from the higher inflation likely to result from the depreciation of sterling. On the other hand, it is lower than we previously projected and should help manage risks to employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The adjusted level reflects the fact that pay growth and forecasts have been weaker than expected and a relative target automatically moves in line with them. A material worsening in economic performance and prospects would lead us next year to consider whether to recommend slower increases than needed to stay on a straight line path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Looking ahead, the cash figure for 2020 is inevitably very uncertain. However, using October 2016 data, we estimate 60 per cent of median earnings will be £8.61, within a range of £8.50 to £8.73. This is down from £9.16 in the spring’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes"&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Low Pay Commission is an independent body made up of employers, trade unions and experts whose role is to advise the Government on minimum wages. The National Living Wage is the legally binding pay floor for workers aged 25 and over. The other minimum wage rates comprise: the 21-24 Year Old Rate, the 18-20 Year Old Rate and the 16-17 Year Old Rate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our remit gives us different requirements in relation to the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; than for the four other bands of the minimum wage.  For the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; we are asked to make recommendations on the pace of increase towards a target: an ‘ambition…that it should continue to increase to reach 60 per cent of median earnings by 2020, subject to sustained economic growth’. For the other rates we are asked to ‘help as many low-paid workers as possible without damaging their employment prospects’.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Our full recommendations for April 2017 are set out in our 18th report, laid in Parliament today, and letter to the Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy, found &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/national-minimum-wage-low-pay-commission-autumn-2016-report"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We said in our last report in February that, in the absence of economic shocks or other strong evidence, we thought that the default for the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; would be a straight line rolling path to the 60 per cent target - spreading our (annually updated) estimate of the increase in relative value needed to hit the target evenly over the remaining years to 2020. Our recommendation today reflects this approach, but the cash level is somewhat lower than expected in the spring when we projected £7.64 for April 2017. This reflects automatic adjustment in the level of the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; target in view of weaker pay growth and forecast pay growth.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The new rate will increase pay for typical minimum wage workers (26 hours) by nearly £300 per year rising to nearly £600 for full-time minimum wage workers.  An increase of 4.2 per cent is, after the introduction of the National Living Wage in April, the largest increase in the main rate of the minimum wage since 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We estimate that the £7.50 rate will raise coverage - the number of workers paid at or below the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; - by up to 390,000, from 1.6 million jobs (6.7 per cent of the cohort) in April 2016 to up to 2.0 million (8.3 per cent) in April 2017. Looking at progress towards the 60 per cent target, we estimate that the £7.50 rate will represent an increase in the relative value of the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; for workers aged 25 and over of 1.1 percentage points, up from 55.8 per cent of the value of typical earnings (October 2016) to 56.8 per cent (October 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rates for workers under 25 and apprentices are lower than the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; in reflection of lower average earnings and higher unemployment rates. International evidence also suggests that younger workers are more exposed to employment risks arising from the pay floor than older workers. Unlike the &lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt; (where some consequences for employment has been accepted by the Government), the &lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt;’s remit requires us to set the other rates as high as possible without causing damage to jobs and hours. Additional considerations this year included: uncertainty in the economy, with any slowdown likely to affect younger workers first, with serious consequences for future employment and earnings; and a new calendar that meant younger workers were getting a minimum wage six months after their last one rather than the usual twelve. The rates for under-25s and apprentices have previously changed on October 1st. In 2017, they will move to an April calendar, increasing at the same time as the National Living Wage, which was introduced to align with the tax year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were also asked to provide an indicative rate for the National Living Wage from April 2018. This is inevitably uncertain because pay forecasts are likely to change, but using those available in October we project that the on-course rate will lie in a range of £7.80-£7.91. Using its forecasts published today, the OBR estimates a figure of £7.90. For 2020, the &lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt;’s projected rate for 60 per cent of median earnings is £8.61, within a range of £8.50 to £8.73. Using its forecasts published today, the OBR estimates a slightly higher figure, of £8.80.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The National Living Wage is different from the UK Living Wage and the London Living Wage. Differences include that: the UK Living Wage and the London Living Wage are voluntary pay benchmarks that employers can sign up to if they wish, not legally binding requirements; the hourly rate of the UK Living Wage and London Living Wage is based on an attempt to measure need, whereas the National Living Wage is based on a target relationship between its level and average pay; the UK Living Wage and London Living Wage apply to workers aged 18 and over, the National Living Wage to workers aged 25 and over. The Low Pay Commission has no role in the UK Living Wage or the London Living Wage.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The members of the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/low-pay-commission"&gt;Low Pay Commission&lt;/a&gt; comprise:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sir David Norgrove, Chair&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Prof. Sarah Brown, Professor of Economics at the University of Sheffield&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kay Carberry, TUC&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Neil Carberry, Director of Employment and Skills, CBI&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clare Chapman, Non-Executive Director &amp;amp; Remuneration Committee Chair at Kingfisher PLC&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Prof. Richard Dickens, Professor of Economics, Sussex University&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Peter Donaldson, Managing Director, D5 Consulting Ltd&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;John Hannett, General Secretary, Usdaw&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Brian Strutton, General Secretary, BALPA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our recommendations comprise:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
&lt;abbr title="Low Pay Commission"&gt;LPC&lt;/abbr&gt; 2016 recommendations for the minimum wage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Oct 2015&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;April 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;October 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;April 2017&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6m increase&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Annual increase&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Increase on Oct 2015&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;abbr title="National Living Wage"&gt;NLW&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£7.20&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£7.50&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21-24 rate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£6.70&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(6.83)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£6.95&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£7.05&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.4%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5.2%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18-20 rate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£5.30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(5.43)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£5.55&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£5.60&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.9%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.1%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5.7%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16-17 rate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£3.87&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(3.94)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£4.00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£4.05&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.25%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.8%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.7%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;App rate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£3.30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;(3.45)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£3.40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;£3.50&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2.9%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.5%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6.1%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press enquiries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: lpc@lowpay.gov.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telephone: 020 7211 8119; 07720 212676&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344735</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:28:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T13:28:38+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/autumn-statement-2016-some-of-the-things-weve-announced"/>
    <title>News story: Autumn Statement 2016: some of the things we've announced</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Chancellor has presented his Autumn Statement to Parliament – here's a summary of what was announced.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="continuing-to-bring-down-the-deficit"&gt;Continuing to bring down the deficit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-economic-forecast"&gt;1. New economic forecast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK economy is forecast to be the fastest growing major economy in 2016, but the Office for Budget Responsibility has forecast growth to slow and inflation to rise over the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But growth remains positive and employment continues to rise in each of the next 5 years, with half a million more people forecast to be in work by 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="debt-falling-by-2020"&gt;2. Debt falling by 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has cut borrowing by nearly two-thirds since 2010, but will no longer aim for a budget surplus (where more tax is raised than is spent) by 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New fiscal targets are needed to provide the flexibility to support the economy and create space for more investment in roads, rail, research, and housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has therefore set new fiscal targets which aim for 2% underlying deficit and debt falling by 2020, and a balanced budget as soon as possible thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="building-an-economy-that-works-for-all"&gt;Building an economy that works for all&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fuel-duty-will-remain-frozen-for-a-seventh-year"&gt;3. Fuel duty will remain frozen for a seventh year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, fuel duty will remain frozen for the seventh successive year, saving drivers £130 a year on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="a-new-three-year-nsi-investment-bond-available-from-spring-2017"&gt;4. A new three-year NS&amp;amp;I Investment Bond available from spring 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support savers, NS&amp;amp;I will offer a new three-year Investment Bond with an indicative rate of 2.2% from spring 2017. The bond will offer the flexibility to put away between £100 and £3,000 and be available to those aged 16 or over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="committing-to-raise-the-personal-allowance-to-12500-and-the-higher-rate-threshold-to-50000-by-2020-21"&gt;5. Committing to raise the Personal Allowance to £12,500 and the Higher Rate Threshold to £50,000 by 2020-21&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Personal Allowance is the amount of income you can earn before you start paying income tax. It is currently £11,000 this year, and will rise to £11,500 in 2017-18. The point at which you pay the higher rate of income tax will increase from £43,000 this year, to £45,000 in 2017-18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the Personal Allowance reaches £12,500, it will increase in line with inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-national-living-wage-and-the-national-minimum-wage-will-increase-from-april-2017"&gt;6. The National Living Wage and the National Minimum Wage will increase from April 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Living Wage for those aged 25 and over will increase from £7.20 per hour to £7.50 per hour. That means over £1,400 a year more for a full-time worker previously on the National Minimum Wage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Minimum Wage will also increase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for 21 to 24 year olds – from £6.95 per hour to £7.05&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for 18 to 20 year olds  – from £5.55 per hour to £5.60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for 16 to 17 year olds – from £4.00 per hour to £4.05&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;for apprentices – from £3.40 per hour to £3.50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And £4.3 million will be spent on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;helping small businesses to understand the rules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cracking down on employers who are breaking the law by not paying the minimum wage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-universal-credit-taper-will-be-reduced-from-65-to-63-from-april-2017"&gt;7. The Universal Credit taper will be reduced from 65% to 63% from April 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Universal Credit, as a person’s income increases, their benefit payments are gradually reduced. The taper rate calculates the reduction in benefits as a person’s salary increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, for every £1 earned after tax above an income threshold, a person receiving Universal Credit has their benefit award reduced by 65p and keeps 35p. They will now keep 37p for every £1, from April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three million households will benefit from this change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a single parent with one child and not receiving support with their housing costs earning £15,000 a year will benefit by £170 a year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a couple with two children receiving support with their housing costs, where one parent earns £30,000 a year, will benefit by £425 a year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a disabled person receiving support with their housing costs and earning £12,000 a year will benefit by £180 a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="a-ban-on-letting-agents-charging-fees-to-renters"&gt;8. A ban on letting agents charging fees to renters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letting agents will no longer be able to charge renters fees, for example when they sign a new tenancy agreement. This will stop tenants being hit with fees averaging £223 per tenancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government will consult on this in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="cracking-down-on-pensions-scams"&gt;9. Cracking down on pensions scams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A consultation before Christmas will look at ways to tackle pensions scams, including banning businesses from cold calling someone about their pension. This includes scammers targeting people who inadvertently ‘opt-in’ to receiving third party communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="over-102-million-of-libor-banking-fines-to-support-armed-forces-and-emergency-services-charities"&gt;10. Over £102 million of LIBOR banking fines to support armed forces and emergency services charities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LIBOR fines are collected from banks who break banking rules, and are given directly to causes benefitting armed forces and emergency services charities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£102 million will go to more than 100 projects supporting armed forces personnel, their families and veterans; emergency service personnel; children’s hospitals, air ambulances and emergency responders; and museums and memorials, over the next 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="investing-in-infrastructure-and-innovation-to-improve-long-term-productivity"&gt;Investing in infrastructure and innovation to improve long-term productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="a-new-national-productivity-investment-fund-to-provide-23-billion-of-additional-spending-ensuring-the-uks-economy-is-fit-for-the-future"&gt;11. A new National Productivity Investment Fund to provide £23 billion of additional spending, ensuring the UK’s economy is fit for the future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Productivity Investment Fund (NPIF) will provide major additional spending in areas that are key to boosting productivity: transport, digital communications, research and development (R&amp;amp;D), and housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="billion-for-a-new-housing-infrastructure-fund"&gt;12. £2.3 billion for a new Housing Infrastructure Fund&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fund will be used for projects such as roads and water connections that will support the construction of up to 100,000 new homes in the areas where they are needed most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, £1.4 billion will be used to provide 40,000 new affordable homes, including some for shared ownership and some for affordable rent. And another £1.7 billion will be used to speed up the construction of new homes on public sector land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="million-investment-in-future-transport-technology"&gt;13. £390 million investment in future transport technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;£390 million will go to future transport technology, including driverless cars, renewable fuels and energy efficient transport. This will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£100 million investment in testing infrastructure for driverless cars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£150 million to provide at least 550 new electric and hydrogen buses, reduce the emissions of 1,500 existing buses and support taxis to become zero emission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£80 million to install more charging points for ultra-low emission vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="a-major-new-investment-in-transport-infrastructure"&gt;14. A major new investment in transport infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the National Productivity Investment Fund, this will cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£1.1 billion to reduce congestion and upgrade local roads and public transport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£220 million to tackle road safety and congestion on Highways England roads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£27 million to develop an expressway connecting Oxford and Cambridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will also be a two-year 100% first year allowance for companies who install electric charge-points, coming in from today‎. This allows companies to deduct the cost of the charge-point from their pre-tax profits in that year‎.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And £450 million will also be spent on trialling railway digital signalling technology which will expand capacity and improve reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="billion-to-invest-in-full-fibre-broadband-and-trialling-5g-networks"&gt;15. £1 billion to invest in full-fibre broadband and trialling 5G networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment will support the private sector to roll out more full-fibre broadband by 2020-21. Funding will also support trials of 5G mobile communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from April 2017, the government will also provide a new 100% business rates relief for new full-fibre infrastructure for a 5 year period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="billion-more-per-year-in-research-and-development-funding-by-2020-21"&gt;16. £2 billion more per year in research and development funding by 2020-21&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major increase in research and development funding for universities and businesses with R&amp;amp;D projects to help the UK remain an attractive place for businesses to invest in innovative research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will back scientific research and development of technologies such as robotics, artificial intelligence and industrial biotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="more-money-for-scotland-wales-and-northern-ireland"&gt;17. More money for Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland will receive more money which can be spent on infrastructure projects, with each devolved administration deciding where this will be spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be an increase of over £800 million for the Scottish Government, over £400 million for the Welsh Government and over £250 million for the Northern Ireland Executive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="expanding-the-museums-and-galleries-tax-relief"&gt;18. Expanding the museums and galleries tax relief&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new museums and galleries tax relief will be expanded to include permanent exhibitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new tax relief, which starts in April 2017, was originally only intended to be available for temporary and touring exhibitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rates of relief will be set at 20% for non-touring exhibitions and 25% for touring exhibitions. The relief will be capped at £500,000 of qualifying expenditure per exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="over-10-million-to-support-culture-and-heritage-projects-across-the-uk"&gt;19. Over £10 million to support culture and heritage projects across the UK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;£7.6 million will cover urgent and essential repairs to the heritage house, Wentworth Woodhouse in South Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other cultural projects will also be supported, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£850,000 for a Royal Society of the Arts pilot to promote cultural education in schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£1.6 million to help complete Studio 144, an arts complex in Southampton, including an auditorium, studio, and gallery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;£1 million towards the development of a new creative media centre in Plymouth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="providing-certainty-for-businesses"&gt;Providing certainty for businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="committing-to-cutting-corporation-tax-to-17-by-2020"&gt;20. Committing to cutting corporation tax to 17% by 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main rate of corporation tax has already been cut from 28% in 2010 to 20%, and will be cut again to 17% by 2020, by far the lowest in the G20 and benefitting over 1 million businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="million-through-the-british-business-bank-to-invest-in-growing-innovative-firms"&gt;21. £400 million through the British Business Bank to invest in growing innovative firms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funds will be invested in innovative small businesses with potential for growth, to provide the finance that they need to expand. This will support up to £1 billion of new investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="rural-rate-relief-will-increase-to-100"&gt;22. Rural Rate Relief will increase to 100%&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rural rate relief will increase from 50 to 100% in April 2017, saving a business up to £2900 a year. This business rate relief is available to businesses in rural areas with a population under 3,000, where that business is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the only village shop or post office with a rateable value of up to £8,500, or&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the only public house or petrol station with a rateable value of up to £12,500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="a-fair-and-sustainable-tax-system"&gt;A fair and sustainable tax system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="cracking-down-on-tax-avoiders-and-those-who-help-them"&gt;23. Cracking down on tax avoiders and those who help them&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new penalty is being introduced for those helping someone else to use a tax avoidance scheme. Tax avoiders are hit with significant bills when HMRC defeats their avoidance scheme, this new penalty will ensure that those who help them will also face the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also tax avoiders will not be able to claim as a defence against penalties that relying on non-independent tax advice is taking reasonable care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="salary-sacrifice-schemes-will-be-taxed-more-fairly"&gt;24. Salary sacrifice schemes will be taxed more fairly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From April 2017, most salary sacrifice schemes will be subject to the same tax as cash income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In salary sacrifice schemes, employees exchange some of their salary for a non-cash benefit in kind (such as a mobile phone). Both the employer and employee make a tax saving, because the benefit is taxed less than a salary or not taxed at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will affect types of salary sacrifice schemes differently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pensions, pensions advice, childcare, Cycle to Work and ultra-low emission cars will be exempt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all arrangements in place before April 2017 will be protected for up to a year, and arrangements in place before April 2017 for cars, accommodation and school fees will be protected for up to 4 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="insurance-premium-tax-will-increase-by-2-from-1-june-2017"&gt;25. Insurance Premium Tax will increase by 2% from 1 June 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insurance Premium Tax (IPT) will increase from 10% to 12%. IPT is a tax on insurers and it is up to them whether and how to pass on costs to customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344847</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:26:38+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T13:26:38+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/800-million-boost-to-scottish-governments-capital-budgets-in-autumn-statement"/>
    <title>News story: £800 million boost to Scottish Government’s capital budgets in Autumn Statement</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Autumn Statement sets out an increase of more than £800 million through to 2020-2021, in the Scottish Government’s budget.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today (23 November 2016) at Autumn Statement, the Chancellor set out announcements which will build an economy that works for everyone, in Scotland and the whole of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK Government’s decision to focus on infrastructure spending means that the Scottish Government’s budget will increase by more than £800 million through to 2020-21, giving it even greater spending power to boost productivity and promote growth in Scotland, all while supported by the broad shoulders of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the increase in capital budget is spent in Scotland is up to the Scottish Government, which has the opportunity to take its own investment decisions as well as using its own tax, borrowing and welfare powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Autumn Statement also includes direct action that will benefit Scotland – such as the Chancellor’s decision to increase investment in research and development by £2 billion a year by 2020-2, which should benefit Scotland’s thriving universities and research and innovation centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the extra spending power made available to the Scottish Government, Scotland’s cities will continue to benefit from further commitments from the UK government, with funding confirmed for city deals in Aberdeen and Inverness, negotiations for a city deal with Edinburgh ongoing and the UK Government prepared to consider proposals from Tay Cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Autumn Statement announces for the first time that the UK government will also open negotiations with Stirling. This means that the UK government will have agreed, or be in discussions with, each of Scotland’s cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK government has also taken actions to support people that are just about managing throughout the UK.  Fuel duty is frozen for the seventh successive year, which should save the average car driver in Scotland £10 each time they fill their tank. The National Living Wage is increasing from £7.20 to £7.50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotland is also benefiting with more than £3.3 million of LIBOR funding raised from fines levied on banks being distributed to good causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the government will meet its manifesto commitment to increase the personal allowance to £12,500. Over the last Parliament, 2.4 million individuals in Scotland saw an average gain of £517, due to an increase to the personal allowance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotland, like the rest of the UK, will benefit from the decisions set out in today’s Autumn Statement, as the UK government builds an economy that works for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State for Scotland, David Mundell said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today’s Autumn Statement will build an economy that works for everyone in Scotland and the rest of the UK. The rise in the National Living Wage means a well deserved pay rise for thousands of Scots, and the freeze in fuel duty will make it about £10 cheaper for drivers every time they fill up their car.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Most significantly for Scotland is the £800 million of extra capital funding. This is as a result of the Chancellor’s decision to invest in infrastructure, but it is for the Scottish Government to step up now. If it is used properly by the Scottish Government, this will make a real difference to productivity, jobs and growth in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;The UK government’s decisions today mean a secure economy based on the broad shoulders of the UK, more funding and more powers for Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344848</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:26:28+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T13:26:28+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/northern-ireland-executive-to-see-250-million-boost-to-capital-budget-in-autumn-statement"/>
    <title>News story: Northern Ireland Executive to see £250 million boost to capital budget in Autumn Statement</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Northern Ireland Executive's budget will receive an increase of more than £250 million through to 2020-2021.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today (23 November 2016) at Autumn Statement, the Chancellor set out announcements which will build an economy that works for everyone, in Northern Ireland, and the whole of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK government’s decision to focus on infrastructure spending means that the Northern Ireland Executive’s budget will increase by more than £250 million through to 2020-2021, giving it greater spending power to boost productivity and promote growth in Northern Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this increase in funding will be allocated will be decided by Northern Ireland Ministers, and will be set out by the Finance Minister when he presents his budget to the Northern Ireland Assembly next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Autumn Statement also includes a range of measures that will directly benefit Northern Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel duty is frozen for the seventh successive year, which should save the average car driver in Northern Ireland £10 each time they fill their tank.  The National Living Wage is increasing from £7.20 to £7.50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northern Ireland’s prestigious universities should also benefit from the UK government’s decision to increase funding for research and innovation by £2 billion a year by 2020-21, ensuring that the UK continues to be a world leader in science and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is also making further investments in digital infrastructure such as fibre broadband and 5G – vital in ensuring that businesses in Northern Ireland are well placed to take advantage of the opportunities presented by new technologies, and reap the benefits of greater connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the government will meet its manifesto commitment to increase the personal allowance to £12,500. Over the last Parliament, 700,000 individuals in Northern Ireland saw an average gain of £522, due to increase to the personal allowance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northern Ireland, like the rest of the UK, will benefit from the decisions set out in today’s Autumn Statement, as the UK Government continues to build an economy that works for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State for Northern Ireland James Brokenshire said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I strongly welcome the Chancellor’s Autumn Statement today which takes forward this government’s commitment to build an economy that works for everyone, in Northern Ireland and the whole of our United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Northern Ireland will benefit from over £250 million infrastructure capital funding which will enable the Executive to invest in key infrastructure projects to support future growth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;New investment in research and development and changes to the corporation tax regime is designed to help business and boost productivity and innovation over the long term. The government remains committed to the devolution of corporation tax to the Executive so long as it demonstrates that its finances are on a sustainable footing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Families and ordinary working people will welcome the rise in the National Living Wage and changes to Universal Credit to ensure people keep more of what they earn. Together with a further freeze in fuel duty saving motorists on average £10 every time they fill up their car, today’s measures will provide greater financial security and help Northern Ireland prosper and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344849</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:26:18+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T13:26:18+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/welsh-government-to-benefit-from-over-400-million-boost-to-capital-budgets-from-autumn-statement"/>
    <title>News story: Welsh Government to benefit from over £400 million boost to capital budgets from Autumn Statement</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Welsh Government's budget will increase by over £400 million through to 2020-21.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today (23 November 2016) at Autumn Statement, the Chancellor set out announcements which will build an economy that works for everyone, in Wales and the whole of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK government’s decision to focus on infrastructure spending means that the Welsh Government’s budget will increase by more than £400 million through to 2020-21, giving it even greater spending power to boost productivity and promote growth in Wales.  This is in addition to the £500 million the Welsh Government will be able to borrow to invest from 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be for the Welsh Government to set out how it intends to use this additional funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autumn Statement also includes a range of measures that will directly benefit people across Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By freezing fuel duty for the seventh year running, the UK government will help save the average driver in Wales up to £10 every time they fill up their car.  The National Living Wage is increasing from £7.20 to £7.50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor’s decision to increase investment in research and development by £2 billion a year by 2020-21 should benefit thriving universities and research centres in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK government is also making further investment in digital infrastructure such as fibre broadband and 5G – this will ensure that businesses across Wales are well placed to take full advantage of the opportunities presented by new technologies, and reap the benefits of greater connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities in Wales will also see the impact of UK government support to unlock their potential, with talks progressing well for a city deal with Swansea, building on the success of the £1.2 billion deal for the Cardiff Capital Region. The UK government will also consider proposals for a growth deal for North Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the government will meet its manifesto commitment to increase the personal allowance to £12,500. Over the last Parliament, 1.2 million individuals in Wales saw an average gain of £521, due to an increase to the personal allowance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Wales is benefiting with more than £3 million of LIBOR funding raised from fines levied on banks being distributed to good causes, including a further £1 million for the Wales Air Ambulance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wales, like the rest of the UK, will benefit from the decisions set out in today’s Autumn Statement as the UK government builds an economy that works for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State for Wales, Alun Cairns said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Chancellor’s Autumn Statement was good news for Wales. Not only does it help build an economy that works for everyone across Wales and the rest of the UK, it provides a significant over £400 million uplift in the Welsh Government’s capital budget. This comes as a result of the Chancellor’s decision to focus on infrastructure, and will allow the Welsh Government to make decisions that will help people across Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;It is an Autumn Statement that contains measures that will help people all over Wales, making it easier for them to save for the future, giving people on the National Living Wage a pay rise and supporting the pioneering work of Wales’ great universities by investing in research and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344811</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T13:25:53+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T13:25:53+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/7-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-budget-timetable"/>
    <title>News story: 7 things you need to know about the new Budget timetable</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>At the Autumn Statement, the Chancellor announced that the government will move to a single major fiscal event each year.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means following the spring 2017 Budget and Finance Bill, Budgets will be delivered in the autumn, with the first one taking place in autumn 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-uk-is-the-only-major-advanced-economy-to-make-major-changes-to-the-tax-system-twice-a-year"&gt;1. The UK is the only major advanced economy to make major changes to the tax system twice a year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses, economy and tax experts like the International Monetary Fund, Institute for Government, the CBI, Chartered Institute of Taxation and the IFS have all been calling for this change. It will mean businesses and people face less frequent changes to the tax system, helping to promote certainty and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="spring-budget-2017-will-be-the-final-budget-held-during-springtime"&gt;2. Spring Budget 2017 will be the final Budget held during springtime&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move to a single fiscal event will be made after the spring Budget in 2017. There will be a second Budget before the end of 2017 to switch to the new timetable, which will then be followed in future years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Office for Budget Responsibility (OBR) is required by law to produce two forecasts a year. One of these will remain at Budget. The other will fall in the spring and the government will respond to it with a Spring Statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="finance-bill-will-follow-the-budget-as-it-does-now"&gt;3. Finance Bill will follow the Budget, as it does now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect a Finance Bill in spring/summer 2017 following the spring Budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From winter 2017, Finance Bills will be introduced following the Budget. The aim will be to reach Royal Assent in the spring, before the start of the following tax year. This change in timetable will help Parliament to scrutinise tax changes before the tax year where most take effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tax-policy-consultation-will-continue-and-be-strengthened"&gt;4. Tax policy consultation will continue and be strengthened&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government remains committed to consulting on policy as set out in ‘&lt;a rel="external" href="http://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20130129110402/http:/www.hm-treasury.gov.uk/d/tax_policy_making_response.pdf.pdf"&gt;The new approach to tax policy making&lt;/a&gt;’ in 2010. Most measures proposed at a Budget will be subject to policy consultation in the spring and publication of draft legislation in the summer, before being legislated in the Finance Bill after the following Budget. To build on this and allow for an earlier stage of involvement on key strategic challenges, the Chancellor has said that he may launch consultations on how to address these longer-term issues at the Spring Statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="from-2018-legislation-day-will-move-to-the-summer"&gt;5. From 2018 ‘Legislation day’ will move to the summer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, most tax policy consultation summaries and draft Finance Bill legislation have been published on ‘Legislation day’, following the Autumn Statement. In 2016 this will be on 5 December. From 2018, under the new timetable, this will move to the summer. As now, the date will continue to be announced by written ministerial statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="an-autumn-budget-means-tax-changes-will-be-announced-well-in-advance-of-the-start-of-the-tax-year"&gt;6. An Autumn Budget means tax changes will be announced well in advance of the start of the tax year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single fiscal event and new timetable to bring forward tax changes so they are legislated for before the start of the tax year will be beneficial to tax stakeholders. Making the transition to the new timetable will require adjustments to the normal tax policy making process due to the shorter interval between the two Budgets. Arrangements will be decided individually for different policies and set out to stakeholders by HMRC. In the normal way, these will where possible provide for consultation on policy proposals and on draft legislation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="will-see-the-first-spring-statement"&gt;7. 2018 will see the first Spring Statement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Spring Statement will respond to the updated OBR forecast for the economy and the public finances. The Chancellor has said that the government will consider longer-term fiscal challenges and start consultations on how they can be addressed. The government will retain the option to make changes to fiscal policy at the Spring Statement if the economic circumstances require it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344748</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T12:40:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T12:40:05+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/open-banking-transformation-moves-a-step-closer"/>
    <title>Press release: Open Banking transformation moves a step closer</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The CMA is today taking the next step towards introducing Open Banking.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The development of Open Banking – the use of technology to provide customers with more control over their accounts and financial services – is one of 17 &lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt;-imposed changes that will make banks work harder for their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other changes, on which the Competition and Markets Authority (&lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt;) is opening a consultation today, will require banks to cap their monthly unarranged overdraft charges, help customers avoid unarranged overdraft charges by making banks text them when they are at risk of going overdrawn, and also help customers compare the service they get from their bank with other banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alasdair Smith, Chairman of the retail banking market investigation, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These reforms will fundamentally transform banking for personal customers and small businesses. They will break down barriers, increase competition and give customers control over their own money.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Taken together we expect our remedies to deliver direct benefits to customers of between £700 million and £1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its final &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-paves-the-way-for-open-banking-revolution"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; published in August this year, the &lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt; announced measures aimed at ensuring that customers benefit from technological advances, and that new entrants and smaller providers can compete more fairly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further measures in today’s consultation include requiring banks to publish rates for small and medium-sized enterprise (&lt;abbr title="small and medium-sized enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt;) lending products and to develop tools to allow for easier comparison of &lt;abbr title="small and medium-sized enterprise"&gt;SME&lt;/abbr&gt; banking products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responses on the 17 measures in the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/cma-cases/review-of-banking-for-small-and-medium-sized-businesses-smes-in-the-uk"&gt;draft order&lt;/a&gt; are invited by 5pm on 23 December by email to &lt;a href="mailto:retailbanking@cma.gsi.gov.uk"&gt;retailbanking@cma.gsi.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt; or by post to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="address"&gt;&lt;div class="adr org fn"&gt;&lt;p&gt;

Project Manager
&lt;br&gt;Retail banking market investigation
&lt;br&gt;Competition and Markets Authority
&lt;br&gt;Victoria House
&lt;br&gt;Southampton Row 
&lt;br&gt;London   WC1A 4AD    
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="notes-for-editors"&gt;Notes for editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt; is the UK’s primary competition and consumer authority. It is an independent non-ministerial government department with responsibility for carrying out investigations into mergers, markets and the regulated industries and enforcing competition and consumer law. For more information on the &lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt; see our &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/competition-and-markets-authority"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt; or follow us on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/CMAgovUK"&gt;@CMAgovuk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/cma-gov-uk/"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/competition-and-markets-authority?trk=tyah&amp;amp;trkInfo=tas%3ACompetition+and+Markets+Authority"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The members of the retail banking market investigation group are: &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cma-panel-member-biographies-and-disclosures-of-interest/inquiry-chairs-biographies#professor-alasdair-smith"&gt;Alasdair Smith&lt;/a&gt; (Chair), &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cma-panel-member-biographies-and-disclosures-of-interest/panel-members-biographies#professor-thomas-hoehn"&gt;Tom Hoehn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cma-panel-member-biographies-and-disclosures-of-interest/inquiry-chairs-biographies#professor-philip-marsden"&gt;Philip Marsden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cma-panel-member-biographies-and-disclosures-of-interest/panel-members-biographies#jill-may"&gt;Jill May&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cma-panel-member-biographies-and-disclosures-of-interest/panel-members-biographies#ed-smith"&gt;Ed Smith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;abbr title="Competition and Markets Authority"&gt;CMA&lt;/abbr&gt; will open a separate consultation on draft undertakings from Bacs next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media enquiries should be directed to Simon Belgard (&lt;a href="mailto:simon.belgard@cma.gsi.gov.uk"&gt;simon.belgard@cma.gsi.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;, 020 3738 6472).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344607</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T12:10:07+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T12:10:07+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-arrangements-at-visitor-moorings-on-the-non-tidal-river-thames"/>
    <title>Press release: New arrangements at visitor moorings on the non-tidal River Thames</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>The Environment Agency is to test new arrangements for managing its short-stay visitor moorings along the non-tidal River Thames.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;During a 12-month trial starting on Wednesday 16 November 2016, Thames Visitor Moorings (TVM), a private company run ‘by boaters for boaters’, will take over responsibility for managing usage and collecting fees at 21 of the 22 visitor mooring sites currently operated by the Environment Agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change will bring significant benefits for boaters and the Environment Agency alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boaters will be able to register their arrival (a condition of use) online or by phone at any time of day, and pay any fees using a debit or credit card, or through Paypal.  At present, they must register their arrival with the duty lock keeper, who can also take cash payments for any fees due. This can cause problems however if the lock keeper is off-duty, working off-site, busy with other duties, or if the boater doesn’t have any cash to hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Environment Agency, the new arrangements are expected to boost the income it receives from its visitor moorings and improve its ability to monitor usage and take enforcement action if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick McKie-Smith, the Environment Agency’s Waterways Operations Enforcement Manager for the non-tidal River Thames said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve got high expectations of this pilot. We’re using a first rate provider who really understands the needs of boaters, and ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I’m confident the new arrangements will hugely improve the customer experience and compliance at our visitor moorings, and increase our revenue. It’s good news for boaters, and for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency and others provide short-stay visitor moorings to facilitate touring on the Thames. Generally, they allow boaters to stay for up to 3 days for a nominal charge to enjoy the facilities and attractions of the local area, before moving on to another location and freeing up the space for someone else to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some boaters stay considerably longer than the maximum allowed, preventing their fellow boaters from using the moorings for their intended purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency introduced new ‘car park’ style terms and conditions at its visitor mooring sites in 2013 and this has vastly improved compliance. These additional new arrangements will improve the management of these sites even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex Walden is the owner/operator of Thames Visitor Moorings. A residential boater and former chair of the Residential Boat Owners’ Association (RBOA), Rex is also a member of the Thames Navigation Users Forum (TNUF), a group representing boaters’ interests in regular discussions with the Environment Agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rex said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I use visitor moorings most of the year. I share the challenges and frustrations of boaters but also understand those of the Environment Agency and the wider riverside community. TVM is born out of my experience. It is genuinely ‘by boaters for boaters’ and is intended to make life easier for all of those who use the river and the organisations who manage it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I hope our activity will help support the development of new visitor moorings being established and an increase in the number of boats using the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="notes-to-editor"&gt;Notes to editor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Environment Agency is the navigation authority for the non-tidal Thames, 135 miles of navigable waterway from Cricklade in Wiltshire, near the river’s source, to Teddington in southeast London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear signage at the mooring sites sets out the conditions of their use. The only change to the existing conditions under the pilot scheme is that users must register their arrival with Thames Visitor Moorings, online or by phone, rather than with the local lock keeper. All other existing conditions and charges  remain the same. At most sites, mooring for up to one day is free, all or part of a second or third day is  £5 for each day, the daily rate from then on is £100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By mooring at any one of the sites, boaters are entering into a contractual agreement to abide by these conditions, which are enforceable under civil proceedings. Any enforcement action will be carried out by NSL Ltd, under existing arrangements, but under the pilot, Thames Visitor Moorings will assist Environment Agency staff to carry out spot checks to identify any non-compliance, details of which will be passed  by the Environment Agency to to NSL Ltd for them to act on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For media enquiries Monday to Friday 9am to 5pm, please call 03708 506 506 
After this time, please call the duty communications officer on 0800 141 2743 or email &lt;a href="mailto:communications_THM@environment-agency.gov.uk"&gt;communications_THM@environment-agency.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow us on Twitter: @EnvAgencySE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344888</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T11:37:32+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T11:37:32+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/foreign-office-minister-alan-duncans-first-visit-to-georgia"/>
    <title>News story: Foreign Office Minister Alan Duncan's first visit to Georgia</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Georgia will host the annual UK-Georgia 'Wardrop' Dialogue for the first time since it was launched in 2014.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Europe and Americas, Sir Alan Duncan, will visit Georgia for the third round of our annual bilateral strategic dialogue, known as the Wardrop Dialogue. During his visit he will meet the President, Prime Minister and Foreign Minister of Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 is the first time the event is taking place in Tbilisi, Georgia. The UK and Georgia will discuss cooperation on security and defence, economic and commercial ties, and the mutual values which underpin an increasingly strong bilateral relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister Sir Alan Duncan said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The UK’s commitment to Georgia, as an international security partner and regional democratic role model, is unwavering.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Through its democratic credentials, open economy and progressive human rights, Georgia is playing a vital role in the stability and security of the wider region. Georgia’s progression towards Euro-Atlantic integration, both through NATO and the EU, will only serve to build on the progress already made.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We are committed to supporting Georgia as it seeks to strengthen democratic institutions, undertake important reforms, and further protect human rights and media freedom. That is why we are continuing our Good Governance Fund, which will provide up to £4.5million over the next year to help these reforms.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;This annual event reflects the long history of unity our nations have enjoyed. I look forward to positive and progressive cooperation with the new democratically-elected government over the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="further-information"&gt;Further information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow Foreign Office Minister Sir Alan Duncan on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/AlanDuncanMP"&gt;@AlanDuncanMP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on Twitter &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/foreignoffice"&gt;@foreignoffice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.facebook.com/foreignoffice?ref=hl"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow the Foreign Office on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.instagram.com/ukforeignoffice/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ukforeignoffice"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/foreign-and-commonwealth-office?trk=biz-companies-cym"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class="contact " id="contact_193"&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class="vcard contact-inner"&gt;

        &lt;div class="email-url-number"&gt;
            &lt;p class="email"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;a class="email" href="mailto:newsdesk@fco.gov.uk"&gt;newsdesk@fco.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="tel"&gt;
              &lt;span class="type"&gt;News Desk &lt;/span&gt;
              020 7008 3100
            &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344820</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T10:48:23+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T10:48:23+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/presentation-slides-from-cde-innovation-network-event-17-november-2016"/>
    <title>News story: Presentation slides from CDE Innovation Network event: 17 November 2016</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The Centre for Defence Enterprise (CDE) held a networking event for science and technology providers in London on 17 November 2016.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the event at the &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.millenniumhotels.com/en/london/the-chelsea-harbour-hotel/?cid=gplaces"&gt;Chelsea Harbour Hotel&lt;/a&gt; in London, details were provided on the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cde-themed-competition-the-future-of-aviation-security"&gt;Future Aviation Security Solutions (&lt;abbr title="Future Aviation Security Solutions"&gt;FASS&lt;/abbr&gt;) competition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim Pennycook, Head of Operations at &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt;, introduced &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt; and give an overview of proof-of-concept research funding opportunities for innovative science and technology providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/cde-innovation-network-event-17-nov-2016"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview of the &lt;abbr title="Future Aviation Security Solutions"&gt;FASS&lt;/abbr&gt; programme was provided by the Home Office and Department for Transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/cde-competition-future-aviation-security-solutions-challenge"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview was then provided about the Joint Security and Resilience Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/an-overview-of-the-joint-security-and-resilience-centre"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific information about the themed competition, which has up to £1 million available for fully funded phase 1 projects, was then provided. There are two technology challenges - screening of people and their hand luggage, and the screening of aviation cargo and hold luggage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/cde-competition-on-fass-technology-challenge-1"&gt;View the presentation slides for the first challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/cde-competition-briefing-fass"&gt;View the presentation slides for the second challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further detail about how the competition works was then provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/an-explanation-on-how-the-cde-competition-works"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Hardie, &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt; Technology Manager briefed on what &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt; is all about, our funding opportunities and how to work with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/an-introduction-to-cde-as-delivered-at-the-innovation-networking-event"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, Bruce also talked about how to create a great &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt; proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.slideshare.net/MOD_CDE/tips-on-how-to-submit-a-great-proposal-to-the-centre-for-defence-enterprise"&gt;View the presentation slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees were also able to book a face-to-face meeting with &lt;abbr title="Centre for Defence Enterprise"&gt;CDE&lt;/abbr&gt; and Home Office and Department for Transport subject matter experts to discuss potential proposals to the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344851</id>
    <published>2016-11-23T06:43:51+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-23T06:43:51+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/uk-india-technology-business-incubator-workshop-in-chennai"/>
    <title>Speech: UK-India Technology Business Incubator workshop in Chennai</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Transcript of speech by British Deputy High Commissioner Chennai Bharat Joshi at UK-India TBI workshop in Chennai , 22 November 2016.
 
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for coming. I’m pleased to be here for the first ever interactive technology business incubator (TBI) stakeholder workshop to exchange best practices between UK and India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our countries are deeply connected, by history, by our diasporas and by our businesses. It was no accident that Theresa May’s first visit as Prime Minister outside of Europe was to India, a clear statement of our commitment to and belief in India as an equal partner. Our future stability and prosperity are mutually reinforcing. The UK is the largest G20 investor in India, investing more than the US and Japan together, while India invests more into the UK than it does the rest of Europe combined. Two weeks ago, I was with both our Prime Ministers at the TECH Summit, an event that showcased the best of Indian and UK innovation in a variety of key sectors including  healthcare and life sciences, automotive, energy, water and smart cities. Innovation and entrepreneurship sat at the heart of the Summit, including in a two day hackathon. As Narendra Modi said ‘Science, technology and innovation have a significant role in India’s bilateral engagement with the UK’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our joint futures are underpinned by our research and development partnership. The UK India research relationship has never been so strong, rising from £1 million in 2009 to over £200 million today, and is growing exponentially. UK and Indian universities are doing more research together than they have ever done before with partner Institutions. New catapult centres and Knowledge transfer networks are bringing together top universities and private sector Institutions to achieve high-value real-world innovation. At the heart of that sits the Newton Bhabha Fund which brings together the UK and Indian scientific research and innovation sectors to find joint solutions to global challenges. The Newton Bhabha Fund is worth £10 million this year and will expand up to £104 million by 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s workshop is about sharing best practice from established technology business incubation managers, projects, ecosystems, real life approaches to challenges from the UK with Indian stakeholders. The UK has a great story to tell: we are third in the Global Innovation Index, a rapid rise from 10th in 2011,  reflecting our strengths of research, scientists, infrastructure and creativity. The UK produces 16% of the top quality published research with less than 1% of the world’s population. Half of our productivity growth between 2000 and 2008 was attributable to innovation. We have invested over £600 million in ‘Eight Great’ emerging technologies where the UK has the depth of research expertise, the business capability to develop a range of applications, and the potential to be at the forefront of commercialisation. This workshop is share some of the lessons we have learned to help develop and grow sustainable incubation centres as key drivers in Prime Minister Modi’s Start-up India initiative. UK companies like Kloudpad – which announced a £50 million production facility for tablets and mobiles in India at the TECH Summit – design in the UK but Make in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to welcome the facilitators for this workshop Mr Martin Garratt, Cambridge Cleantech and Mr Karthik Durgaprasad, Basildon Borough Council and colleagues from Basildon Borough Council, UK as well as incubation managers from leading Indian incubation centres present here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK has a range of offers for budding entrepreneurs, including the Sirius Programme which supports graduate entrepreneurs from around the world looking to start their venture in the UK, the Global Entrepreneurship Programme that helps overseas entrepreneurs and early stage technology businesses or start-ups that want to relocate their business to the UK. We also offer our largest global scholarship scheme anywhere in the world here in India, led by our flagship Chevening Scholarships and Fellowships for Future Leaders, as well as Commonwealth Scholarships and British Council awards. Please do help get the word out to your best and brightest students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks again for attending. I wish you all a very productive day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344813</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T19:05:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T19:05:56+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/faster-entry-at-the-border-now-available-to-uruguayans"/>
    <title>News story: Faster entry at the border now available to Uruguayans</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Regular visitors to the UK from Uruguay are eligible to apply to join the UK’s Registered Traveller Service from Monday 21 November.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Registered Traveller Service provides approved members, who have undergone advanced security checks an expedited clearance through the UK border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UK Immigration Minister Robert Goodwill said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The UK is open for business and I am excited we are going to be able to share in the benefits of Registered Traveller with Uruguay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We know there are thousands of passengers welcomed in the UK from Uruguay each year and the Registered Traveller Service offers them faster entry when they arrive at our border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The scheme is already available to a number of countries across the world and I am very pleased to welcome Uruguay to the Registered Traveller community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be eligible to apply, passengers must hold an eligible passport, have a visa/entry clearance or have visited the UK at least four times in the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registered Traveller allows approved members, who have undergone advanced security checks, faster entry at the UK border through access to the ePassport gates (if they hold an ePassport) or the UK/EU passport lane and do not need to fill in a landing card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals who meet the eligibility criteria may apply to join the Registered Traveller Service online by providing personal details and passport details. Once background checks have been carried out, if the application is successful, the individual will be sent a provisional acceptance letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To validate and confirm their membership, the individual must present themselves on their next arrival in the UK to a Border Force officer where the membership process will be completed with an interview to determine the applicant’s suitability for the service and identity checks are carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344844</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T18:29:45+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T18:29:45+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/tackling-water-insecurity-at-a-global-level-will-need-to-be-a-joint-effort-and-a-joint-investment-one-requiring-regional-cooperation"/>
    <title>Speech: "Tackling water insecurity at a global level will need to be a joint effort and a joint investment, one requiring regional cooperation."</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Statement by Ambassador Matthew Rycroft, UK Permanent Representative to the United Nations, at the UN Security Council Open Debate on Water, Peace and Security</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you Mr President.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the outset let me welcome the analysis shared by the Secretary-General and all our briefers this morning. And I join others in paying tribute to you, Mr President, for your leadership in bringing this vital issue to the Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important part of our responsibilities as the Security Council in delivering Sustainable Development Goal 16 is having a broad enough definition of the threats to international peace and security, not to encroach on the responsibilities of other parts of the UN system, but to join up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on this, Senegal is providing leadership and putting that leadership into practice, through the Senegal River Basin Organisation. I commend the cooperation that you have fostered with Mali, Mauritania and Guinea on flood defences and hydropower. It’s is a welcome example of managing transboundary water challenges through cooperation rather than conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sadly, we’re in need of more examples of best practice. The statistics speak for themselves. Unless we take action, in less than 10 years time, up to two and a half billion people – that’s a third of today’s global population - could be vulnerable to water insecurity.  Unless we take action, by 2030 – the year that we’re supposed to have achieved the Global Goals, including SDG 6 on water and sanitation – then global demand for freshwater will outstrip supply by 40%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr President, this is a problem not just for tomorrow, but for today. Every year water insecurity costs the global economy $500 billion. That’s 500 billion lost to inadequate water and sanitation, lost to urban flood damage, lost to agriculture wastage through droughts and floods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the people affected by this issue today, it’s about much more than money. It’s about life and death. Take the villagers of Kiangwe, in Lamu County in Kenya. Water scarcity there means that inhabitants spend sleepless nights walking to dried up wells in the hope of securing just a few bottles of water. It means them choosing to risk their lives by walking through territory full of Al Shabaab fighters. It means leaving their children at home, alone, hungry and thirsty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from that village in Kenya, you can extrapolate and see the risk that this issue poses to international peace and security. Scarcity of water affects food and energy production, damaging economic growth. It increases local tensions, causing conflicts over access to water within states as well as within regions.  And as demand increases, it is possible that such conflicts will broaden to include member states themselves or even lead to the targeting of water infrastructure. So I fully endorse the remarks that the briefers made about respecting international humanitarian law and about the importance of protecting water infrastructure. I also like the idea that we heard earlier about water related ceasefires in conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what more can be done? Well, the United Kingdom is already active in helping to tackle this set of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next four years, the UK will be contributing $43 million to improve the management of shared waters in Southern Africa. We’ll be doing so in partnership with the German Ministry for Economic Cooperation and with the Climate Resilient Infrastructure Development Facility, which is a private sector organisation that designs and finances water infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an increasingly water-scarce region, this programme will help SADC countries build water infrastructure, such as storage reservoirs, irrigation, and water supply systems. It will enable countries to share data on water levels with their neighbours to allow timely flood and drought warnings. And it will build the capacity of the institutions such as River Basin Organisations to help them manage water resources in shared river basins, and in doing so it will help countries in the region use these resources to grow their economies and reduce poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most importantly, we expect this programme to help up to 3 million of the poorest people in the region so that they can cope better with the impacts of climate variability and climate change – particularly floods and drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we won’t be doing this alone. Through this project we hope to raise nearly $500 million from the private sector, including companies with a high dependency on water, as well as from national governments and development banks, so that together we can plan and construct water infrastructure for communities within SADC member states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, ultimately, tackling water insecurity at a global level will need to be a joint effort and a joint investment, one requiring regional cooperation. Holding this Security Council session is an important step towards that collective, cooperative effort. And we shouldn’t underestimate the scale of the challenge ahead. The global investment deficit for water governance and infrastructure alone is $198 billion per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But together we can make a difference if we invest in the information, the institutions and the infrastructure required to deliver water security. And when combined with the right political interventions, including by this Security Council, we can together reduce the impact of water problems at local, national and regional levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344839</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T17:51:48+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T17:51:48+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-meeting-with-prime-minister-michel-of-belgium-22-november-2016"/>
    <title>Press release: PM meeting with Prime Minister Michel of Belgium: 22 November 2016</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Prime Minister Theresa May met with the Belgian Prime Minister Charles Michel to discuss issues including Brexit and counter-terrorism.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Downing Street spokesperson said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister welcomed Prime Minister Charles Michel of Belgium to Downing Street this morning for bilateral talks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister updated Prime Minister Michel on the process for the UK leaving the EU and reiterated that she intends to trigger Article 50 by the end of March next year. She confirmed that while we are leaving the EU we are not leaving Europe and want to maintain strong relationships with all member states as well as with the EU itself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The leaders discussed the recent US election and the Prime Minister emphasised that a strong transatlantic relationship remains the foundation of global security and prosperity. They also discussed Russia and the importance of finding a solution to the conflict in Syria.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;On counter-terrorism, they agreed that police and the security services should continue to work closely together to ensure the safety of both UK and Belgian nationals. They stated that this was a good example of the strong connection between our 2 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344664</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T16:29:27+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T16:29:27+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/land-registry-awards-local-land-charges-contract"/>
    <title>News story: Land Registry awards Local Land Charges contract</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>We have awarded the Local Land Charges Register Service Build Partner contract to Kainos.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kainos will work with the existing Land Registry in-house development team to build the single Local Land Charges digital register for England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more about &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/local-land-charges"&gt;Local Land Charges&lt;/a&gt;, or read more about &lt;a rel="external" href="http://blog.landregistry.gov.uk/category/local-land-charges/"&gt;our work on the Local Land Charges programme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344808</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T15:40:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T15:40:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/frequently-asked-questions"/>
    <title>Government response: Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <category label="Government response" term="Government response"/>
    <summary>To help keep people informed about our work, we have compiled answers to the questions we get asked most about the UK's departure from the European Union.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;h2 id="the-referendum"&gt;The Referendum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="will-there-be-a-second-referendum-or-an-alternative-to-leaving-the-eu"&gt;Will there be a second referendum or an alternative to leaving the EU?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. The country voted to leave the European Union and it is the duty of the Government and Parliament to make sure we do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-will-you-take-into-account-the-views-of-those-who-did-not-vote-to-leave-the-eu"&gt;How will you take into account the views of those who did not vote to leave the EU?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our priority is to build a national consensus around our exit from the EU. We have already started a wide-ranging programme of engagement, listening to organisations, institutions and companies in as many sectors as possible to establish their priorities and understand their concerns, and also to hear what they think the opportunities are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="exiting-the-european-union"&gt;Exiting the European Union&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-is-article-50-and-why-do-we-need-to-trigger-it"&gt;What is Article 50 and why do we need to trigger it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules for exiting the EU are set out in Article 50 of the Treaty on European Union. This is the only lawful route for withdrawal from the EU under the Treaties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="when-will-article-50-be-triggered"&gt;When will Article 50 be triggered?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister has made clear the Government’s intention to trigger Article 50 no later than the end of March 2017. It is in everyone’s interest that we take time to establish a UK approach and clear objectives for negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-is-the-government-doing-ahead-of-triggering-article-50"&gt;What is the Government doing ahead of triggering article 50?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department for Exiting the European Union is responsible for overseeing negotiations to leave the EU and establishing the future relationship between the UK and EU. The Department now has just over 300 staff in London and a further 120 people working in the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/world/uk-representation-to-the-eu"&gt;UK Representation in Brussels&lt;/a&gt;. We are currently undertaking 2 broad areas of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We are listening to as many organisations, companies and institutions as possible – from the large PLCs to small business, from the devolved administrations through to councils, local government and the major metropolitan bodies – to build a national consensus around our negotiating position. We are doing this through &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/latest?departments%5B%5D=department-for-exiting-the-european-union"&gt;meetings&lt;/a&gt;, visits and a series of sector roundtables, led by the Secretary of State. You can read more about the work of each roundtable, as well as future roundtables and Ministerial visits &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-exiting-the-european-union"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We are carrying out a programme of sectoral and regulatory analysis, which will identify the key factors for British businesses and the labour force that will affect our negotiations with the EU.
This will help inform our negotiating position and build a detailed understanding of how withdrawing from the EU will affect our domestic policies, to seize the opportunities and ensure a smooth process of exit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="does-parliament-need-to-vote-on-triggering-article-50"&gt;Does Parliament need to vote on triggering Article 50?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Government’s position is clear. This is a prerogative power and one that can be exercised by the Government, and we aim to prove that in the Supreme Court. Both Houses of Parliament legislated for the referendum, with cross-party support, and it was clear that it was for the people to decide whether to remain in the EU or leave it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-model-will-be-pursued-in-the-negotiation"&gt;What model will be pursued in the negotiation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our vision for Britain outside the EU is clear: a fully independent, sovereign country. We are not looking for an ‘off the shelf’ deal for our future relationship – a Norwegian model or a Swiss model – it’s going to be an agreement between an independent, sovereign UK and the EU. We want that relationship to reflect the kind of mature, cooperative relationship that close friends and allies enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-will-happen-after-we-leave-the-eu"&gt;What will happen after we leave the EU?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Communities Act will be repealed on the day we leave the EU – meaning that the authority of EU law in Britain will end. We will convert the body of existing EU law into domestic law and then Parliament will be free to amend, repeal and improve any law it chooses. More information on the Great Repeal Bill is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="migration"&gt;Migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-will-you-be-doing-about-immigration--freedom-of-movement"&gt;What will you be doing about immigration / freedom of movement?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DExEU is working closely with the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/home-office"&gt;Home Office&lt;/a&gt; and other Government departments to identify and develop options to shape our future immigration system, including considering the best way to control the number of people coming to the UK following our exit from the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At every step of these negotiations we will work to ensure the best possible outcome for the British people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="i-am-a-eu-national-living-in-the-uk---what-does-exiting-the-eu-mean-for-me"&gt;I am a EU national living in the UK - what does exiting the EU mean for me?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been no change to the rights and status of EU nationals in the UK, or of UK citizens in the EU, as a result of the referendum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister has been clear that during negotiations she wants to protect the status of EU nationals already living here, and the only circumstances in which that wouldn’t be possible is if UK citizens’ rights in European member states were not protected in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more advice for &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-the-status-of-eu-nationals-in-the-uk"&gt;EU citizens living in the UK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="i-am-a-uk-national-living-in-the-eu-what-does-exiting-the-eu-mean-for-my-rights-eg-status-healthcare-pension"&gt;I am a UK national living in the EU, what does exiting the EU mean for my rights (e.g. status, healthcare, pension)?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister has been clear that she wants to protect the rights of UK citizens living in European member states, in the same way that we want to protect the status of EU nationals already living here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At every step of these negotiations we will work to ensure the best possible outcome for the people of the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more advice for &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/advice-for-british-nationals-travelling-and-living-in-europe"&gt;UK nationals in the EU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-will-our-future-immigration-system-look-like"&gt;What will our future immigration system look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a complex issue and DExEU is working closely with the Home Office and other Government departments to identify and develop options to shape our future immigration system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to see net migration to the UK fall to sustainable levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On non-EU migration we have already acted to clamp down on abuses, such as bogus colleges and sham marriages, and we will go further in the months ahead. And now that we are leaving the EU we have an opportunity to gain control on the numbers of people coming here from Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK needs a fair and controlled immigration policy and that is exactly what this government will deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="trade-and-the-single-market"&gt;Trade and the Single Market&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="now-we-have-a-department-for-international-trade-and-for-exiting-the-eu-who-is-responsible-for-what"&gt;Now we have a Department for International Trade and for Exiting the EU, who is responsible for what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-exiting-the-european-union"&gt;Department for Exiting the European Union&lt;/a&gt; oversees negotiations to leave the EU and leads on establishing a new trade and economic relationship with the EU as part of the overall negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-international-trade"&gt;Department for International Trade&lt;/a&gt; leads on boosting UK trade: promoting the UK as a place to do business and trade with; driving inward investment; and, in time, negotiating trade deals and free trade agreements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-will-exiting-the-eu-affect-trade"&gt;How will exiting the EU affect trade?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the EU offers us an opportunity to forge a new role for ourselves in the world: to negotiate our own trade agreements and to be a positive and powerful force for free trade. We recognise the need for a smooth transition which minimises disruption to our trading relationships, including with developing countries. There will be no immediate changes to our relationship with the EU. Until we have left, the UK will remain a member of the EU with all of the rights and obligations that membership entails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="will-we-remain-a-member-of-the-single-market-or-customs-union"&gt;Will we remain a member of the Single Market or Customs Union?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Prime Minister said: we want British companies to have the maximum freedom to trade with and operate in the Single Market – and to let European businesses do the same here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are different aspects to the Customs Union which is why it is important to look at the detail and get the answer right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="eu-funding-projects"&gt;EU Funding Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-will-happen-to-the-future-of-eu-funding-for-uk-projects"&gt;What will happen to the future of EU funding for UK projects?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be no immediate change. The UK will remain a member of the EU until its exit and so continues to pay into the EU and continues to receive funds. The UK will continue to have all of the rights, obligations and benefits that membership brings, up until the point we leave the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognise that many organisations across the UK which are in receipt of EU funding, or expect to start receiving funding, want reassurance about the flow of funding they will receive. That is why we are confirming that structural and investment funds projects signed before the Autumn Statement and Horizon research funding granted before we leave the EU will be guaranteed by the Treasury after we leave. Thousands of British organisations have received guarantees over EU funding from the Chancellor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government will work on subsequent funding arrangements as part of our negotiations to leave the EU and will give more information in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more detailed information on this from &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/chancellor-philip-hammond-guarantees-eu-funding-beyond-date-uk-leaves-the-eu"&gt;HM Treasury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="legislation"&gt;Legislation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-is-the-great-repeal-bill"&gt;What is the Great Repeal Bill?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a piece of legislation which will stop the European Communities Act 1972 from applying in the UK on the day we leave the EU. This ‘Great Repeal Bill’ will end the authority of EU law and return power to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Bill does not prejudge the negotiation. It will not affect when the Prime Minister triggers Article 50 of the Lisbon Treaty, which is what starts the process of our negotiation for leaving the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about ensuring that our exit is smooth and orderly, which is in the best interests of the UK and our EU partners. There are decades of EU law to consider, and we must ensure our laws work when we leave and that we provide the maximum possible stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-will-we-assess-what-eu-laws-we-need"&gt;How will we assess what EU laws we need?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Government departments are currently reviewing the EU laws that apply in their policy areas and how our withdrawal from the EU will affect the operation of those laws. Where laws need to be fixed, that’s what the Government will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="devolution"&gt;Devolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how-will-the-government-ensure-the-views-of-the-scottish-government-welsh-assembly-and-northern-ireland-executive-are-heard"&gt;How will the Government ensure the views of the Scottish Government, Welsh Assembly and Northern Ireland Executive are heard?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working closely with the devolved administrations to get the best possible deal for all parts of the UK as we leave the EU. The Prime Minister is committed to engaging with the Joint Ministerial Committee, bringing together the devolved administrations and the UK Government. This will ensure cooperation and consensus between governments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will give the devolved administrations every opportunity to have their say as we form our negotiating strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="will-the-government-respect-calls-for-a-second-scottish-independence-referendum"&gt;Will the Government respect calls for a second Scottish independence referendum?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the Scottish people decided in a legal, fair and decisive Referendum to remain part of a strong UK. That result should be respected. And that is how we will approach our negotiations for leaving the EU: together as one United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344796</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T15:11:28+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T15:11:28+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/flood-risk-continues-as-communities-urged-to-take-care"/>
    <title>Press release: Flood risk continues as communities urged to take care</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Flood statement 22 November 2016</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the recent heavy rainfall, flooding and disruption could continue to affect some communities in south west and north east England today (Tuesday). There is some continuing flood risk in Dorset and York as yesterday’s rain causes the rivers to gradually rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environment Agency teams are continuing to work hard to reduce flood risk by putting up temporary barriers, operating flood gates and using pumps. Teams are out on the ground monitoring river levels, checking and maintaining flood defences and clearing blockages in watercourses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather will continue to improve this week, but people should avoid walking near swollen rivers and should not risk driving or walking through flood water. Strong winds and large waves will also ease around the coast today, but people should take care when walking by the sea. Information about flood warnings and alerts is updated every 15 minutes on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://flood-warning-information.service.gov.uk/warnings#flood-warnings"&gt;GOV.UK&lt;/a&gt; and people can check their postcodes and sign up to receive free flood warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clare Dinnis, National Flood Duty Manager at the Environment Agency, said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After heavy rain over the last three days and showers forecast today, people in the south west and north east need to be aware of the potential for further flooding.  The weather is due to improve later this week, but we want to remind people not to risk driving through flood water, walking near large waves or near swollen rivers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Environment Agency teams have been out in their communities throughout the night working to reduce flood risk. Temporary flood defences have been deployed and we are continuing to maintain flood defences, clear blockages in watercourses and monitor water levels.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;We know how devastating flooding can be and our hearts go out to those affected. We urge people to check their flood risk on GOV.UK or call Floodline for advice on 0345 988 1188.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344765</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T14:55:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T14:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/carbon-monoxide-poisoning-fatality-cardiff"/>
    <title>News story: Carbon monoxide poisoning fatality, Cardiff</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Owner of motor cruiser Vasquez alongside in Cardiff found deceased on board,</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;MAIB is conducting a preliminary assessment of a fatal accident that occurred on a privately owned cabin cruiser at Cardiff Yacht Club on Saturday 12 November 2016. Shortly after midday the boat’s owner was found collapsed on the boat and despite the efforts of fellow club members and emergency services he did not regain consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of the accident the boat was secured to a club pontoon. The inboard petrol engine was running and the canvas cockpit canopy was fully closed except for one zip that was undone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approximately 45 minutes after he had started the engine, the owner was discovered collapsed in the cabin. Two club members boarded the boat and began to administer CPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paramedics arrived and immediately recognised that the rescuers were displaying symptoms consistent with carbon monoxide (CO) poisoning. They removed the cockpit cover and continued to administer CPR to the owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner was transported to hospital but was later pronounced deceased. Both rescuers were confirmed as suffering from CO poisoning and treated in hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial MAIB tests showed high levels of CO inside the cockpit with the engine running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat was not fitted with a CO detector/alarm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our investigation is independent of any investigation carried out by the Maritime and Coastguard Agency and the police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/email-signup/new?email_signup%5Bfeed%5D=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gov.uk%2Fgovernment%2Forganisations%2Fmarine-accident-investigation-branch.atom"&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to automated emails notifying you when we publish our reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344781</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T14:39:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T14:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/greg-hands-speech-at-eic-connect-oil-gas-2016"/>
    <title>Speech: Greg Hands speech at EIC Connect Oil &amp; Gas 2016</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Speech delivered by Greg Hands, Minister of State for Trade and Investment in Manchester.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you - delighted to be here. As the MP for Chelsea, it is always good to be in Manchester after 6 successive Premier League victories, but fortunately for Mancunians, I am here to talk oil and gas, not football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 2 days, EIC Connect will provide an ideal opportunity for UK businesses to forge new partnerships, explore new markets and highlight the strong skills base we have in the UK, which has proven so successful in securing business overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank the EIC team for making this event happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK’s energy supply chain is world-leading and it is vital that we continue to support this industry in showcasing the very best the UK has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a good story to tell – particularly in the oil and gas sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK started off small: using oil shale from Dorset to light the streets of Wareham with 130 gas lamps in the 1850s, through a company called Wanostrocht and Company. The same company also became the UK’s first oil and gas exporter with a contract to light the streets of Paris!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A century later, in 1964, the first licences were issued for the extraction of oil and gas from the North Sea: about 42 billion barrels of oil have since been produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still more available: 10 to 20 billion barrels according to the Oil &amp;amp; Gas Authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK’s oil production capacity is now the largest in the European Union and within the top 25 of global oil producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our 300 offshore fields in production provided 68% of the UK’s primary energy in 2014 and directly and indirectly support 330,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And currently our oil and gas sector exports over £20 billion per annum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people think this sector is just the prize of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its supply chain touches all parts of the UK: across the entire breadth of the Northern Powerhouse right down to the South East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UK capability is also revered across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In over 100 years of UK onshore exploration and 50 years’ experience in the North Sea, we can now boast world class expertise in exploration and subsea engineering production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we’re taking our expertise around the world: whether that be through large engineering companies such Amec Foster Wheeler, who this year won a great contract in Mozambique, or smaller firms such as EM&amp;amp;I, who having joined a Department for International Trade (&lt;abbr title="Department for International Trade"&gt;DIT&lt;/abbr&gt;) mission to Brazil, won contracts worth over £6.6 million with major international oil and gas companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the UK continues to attract investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International giants such as Halliburton and Baker Hughes service much of the Middle East and Africa from the UK - and they invest heavily in our science, to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s safe to say that we’ve come a long way from the gas lamps of Wareham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And looking to the future, we must lead the way in identifying ways to continue to meet the growing global demands for energy - which are expected to increase to the oil equivalent of 18 billion tons by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By embracing technology, we can meet the world’s energy needs in ways that are sustainable, safe and environmentally friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My message today is simple. When our oil and gas sector succeeds, the whole of the UK succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This government will ensure that we help UK companies up and down the supply chain, to ensure we remain one of the leading lights in this sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the brief time I have today, I want to outline some of the work government is doing to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start by setting the context. Following the formation of our new Department for International Trade in July, trade became front and centre of this country’s future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department for International Trade was established with the primary purpose of ensuring UK becomes a beacon for open trade around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department will develop, coordinate and deliver new trade and investment policy for the UK, including negotiating new trading arrangements with non-EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am delighted that trade is back at the heart of government, with a seat at the cabinet table, and that promoting the UK’s fantastic oil and gas industry falls under my remit as Minister of State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what have been clearly challenging times for the energy sector, I have been genuinely impressed by how firms have adapted and innovated to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you have helped drive down unit operating costs in the UK continental shelf by nearly 30%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenging conditions facing the industry, there is still a sizeable prize for UK companies to fight for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between now and 2020, oil companies are predicted to spend more than $2 trillion and we believe that, based on UK supply chain capabilities, $500 billion of that spend is accessible to our companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My department will rally the whole of government to help the UK win these contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister’s appointed &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/groups/trade-envoys"&gt;Trade Envoys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/groups/business-ambassadors"&gt;Business Ambassadors&lt;/a&gt; will use their experience, and knowledge, to ensure you have the best chance to land these deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Baroness Nicholson, the UK’s trade envoy to Azerbaijan, will be leading a delegation of 23 UK companies to Baku, later this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are already working with firms such as Shell and BP in the Caspian, and Nigeria, to find local supply chain gaps and match them to UK companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our oil and gas high value campaigns are active in 13 markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in our Kazakhstan programme we have facilitated 51 local partnerships and helped UK companies win over £6 billion in contracts, since 2011/12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government is also removing some of the historic barriers that have long deterred UK firms from exporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have heard of our Exporting is GREAT campaign, which was launched last year to inspire and support UK companies to seize the huge global appetite for our goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are live business leads for the energy sector on the &lt;a rel="external" href="https://www.exportingisgreat.gov.uk/opportunities"&gt;GREAT.gov.uk website&lt;/a&gt; – for which UK companies can apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brazil wants our air and gas compressors for their oil and gas industry, Turkey wants specialist equipment for an oil pipeline and Poland needs help constructing a gas pipeline in the south of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in India, where I visited earlier this month with the Secretary of State and the Prime Minister, they are looking to the UK to help enhance their subsea capability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The demand really is out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some businesses tell me that lack of access to finance is another barrier to exporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should check out &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/uk-export-finance"&gt;UK Export Finance&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;abbr title="UK Export Finance"&gt;UKEF&lt;/abbr&gt;), the government’s credit agency, which provided £586 million worth of support for exports in the energy sector in the last financial year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Forum Energy Technologies, which manufacture remotely operated sub-sea vehicles, recently won a contract in Nigeria, thanks to buyer finance provided by &lt;abbr title="UK Export Finance"&gt;UKEF&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of exporting are well known – it increases profitability, enhances resilience and improves productivity. However, the importance to this particular sector should not be underestimated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research by EY shows that around 40% of revenues in the oil and gas supply chain come from exports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the research also suggests that this revenue is delivered by a relatively small number of companies: 50% of exports from less than 10% of companies and 80% of exports from around 25% of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are many companies in the supply chain where export revenue is a small part of their business or, more worryingly, plays no role at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows an incredible amount of unfulfilled potential in this sector and our economy as a whole. I want to work together with industry to see this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who think all this support will change after we leave the EU, let me reassure you: it won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the EU gives us an opportunity to reset and enhance our trading relations with the rest of Europe and the wider world. And we will do so in a way that puts the interests of Britain first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why my department is not designing our trading future in isolation – we are consulting with businesses, academics and trade experts from the UK and around the world to ensure we end up with a deal that is right for Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may be leaving the EU, but we are re-joining the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still seeing investment pour into the UK after the referendum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is due to the UK’s strong economic fundamentals: a skilled workforce fed by some of the world’s best universities, and a low tax, low regulation economy in the right time zone for global trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fundamentals explain why we continue to enjoy record numbers in employment, a growing manufacturing sector, and why we remain the highest ranked major economy for ease of doing business, according to the World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With central government policies that help to address these conditions, the growth of these types of companies can be sustainably accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this reassures me that the UK will be a leader in the global energy market for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the expertise, the will of both industry and government, and now the chance to chart our own trading future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to conclude:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the right focus on the development of partnerships, technology transfer and investment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe it is possible to support further production growth, develop new capacity, open new markets and create the right environment to secure investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All companies need support and the right conditions to help them to thrive, but we must also be prepared to be more ambitious, take measured risks and look further afield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited about what we can still achieve, and I hope you are too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish this conference every success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344795</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T14:38:20+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T14:38:20+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-parole-board-rules-2016"/>
    <title>News story: New Parole Board Rules 2016</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The new Parole Board Rules laid before Parliament on 1st November 2016 come into force today.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Parole Board Rules have been revised to address the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Giving effect to a ministerial decision to allow the release of IPP prisoners without an oral hearing;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aligning the Rules more closely with current operational processes; in particular the Member Case Assessment process introduced in 2014, under which all cases undergo an initial assessment by a single member at the paper stage;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating and clarifying the language and drafting; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allowing greater flexibility as to the member who makes decisions and deals with applications at different stages in the parole process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Parole Board Rules 2011 and 2014 Amendment Rules are revoked. The 2016 Rules apply to all cases referred to the Board. Cases already referred before the date on which the Rules came into force (22nd November 2016) will continue under the new Rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an overview of the new Rules with key points highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rule 8 (withholding information or reports/non-disclosure) – This rule does not change the substance of the non-disclosure application process but now sets it out in more detail. For instance the requirement for the prisoner’s representative to give an undertaking is now express; time periods for parties to appeal, file representations on appeals, and for the Secretary of State to withdraw have been limited to 7 days (although these may be extended if appropriate, under rule 13(2) below); members have an express power to make directions to enable determination of the application, for example to get more information. There has been no change to the grounds for non-disclosure or the test.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rule 9 (representations by and evidence of the parties) – this rule provides a process for parties when evidence is submitted less than 14 days before the hearing. Evidence submitted less than 14 days before the hearing will be accepted at the discretion of the chair, and parties must give reasons for late service (which could be done orally at the hearing). When considering whether to accept evidence, members should consider fairness to the prisoner. If a member specifies a later deadline, that would override this rule. This rule change addresses a gap in the process. It is intended to encourage parties to submit evidence on time. It is not intended to create a bottleneck and parties/stakeholders will take time to adjust to this rule.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rule 12 (adjournment and deferral) – Decisions to adjourn or defer an oral hearing must be recorded in writing with reasons and must be provided to the parties within 14 days. This rule change brings the position for adjournment/deferral notices in line with the current requirements for decisions following oral hearings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rule 13(2) (time) – This new rule allows a member to change any period of time in the Rules where it is appropriate to do so. Members may wish to lengthen or shorten timescales. Members should have a cogent reason for varying the time period and take into account fairness to prisoner as this decision could be subject to legal challenge. It is not appropriate for this rule to be used to vary the timeframe for submitting decision letters and adjournment/deferral notices. Where a panel is waiting for further information following an oral hearing before issuing the panel’s decision, the panel chair should issue an adjournment notice, rather than extending the timeframe for issuing their decision.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rule 14 (consideration by a single member) – This rule corresponds to the MCA stage of the parole process. Aside from the change to permit the release of IPP prisoners without an oral hearing, it reflects the current position under MCA. The options at MCA for indeterminate sentence prisoners other than IPPs (i.e. lifers) are set out in (1) to (3) and then all other cases where release is at issue are covered in (4) (i.e. IPP and determinate cases). Advice cases are covered under (5). 
There will be a period of adjustment for members, stakeholders and Secretariat staff to become familiar with the new Rules. Your patience is therefore appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Parole Board Rules can be found &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2016/1041/contents/made"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344784</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T14:00:41+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T14:00:41+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/serving-prisoner-to-spend-longer-in-prison-after-sexually-assaulting-another-inmate"/>
    <title>Press release: Serving prisoner to spend longer in prison after sexually assaulting another inmate</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Court of Appeal has increased the sentence of serving prisoner following Attorney General referral</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Court of Appeal has today increased the sentence of serving prisoner, John Christon, for sexually assaulting a fellow prisoner in 2 separate attacks over Christmas 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christon, 27, was serving a sentence for breaching his notification requirements at HMP Nottingham when he committed the offences. Christon pleaded guilty to multiple charges of sexual assault and sexual assault by penetration, and received a 9 month sentence at Nottingham Crown Court in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a referral by Attorney General Jeremy Wright QC MP, the Court of Appeal has increased the sentence to 5 years’ imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the hearing, the Attorney General said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I referred this case to the Court of Appeal as I believe the original sentence did not reflect the particularly violent nature of the attacks that the victim was subjected to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hope this serves as reassurance that crimes of this nature will be taken seriously by the Courts, regardless of the victim’s current status as a prisoner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344772</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T13:27:30+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T13:27:30+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/340000-maintenance-programme-for-m6-and-a66-bridges-in-cumbria"/>
    <title>Press release: £340,000 maintenance programme for M6 and A66 bridges in Cumbria</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>A £340,000 programme of bridge improvements along sections of the M6 and A66 in Cumbria will start at the end of the month.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Highways England is improving maintenance access to Kentigern Bridge along the A66 near Keswick as well as to 4 bridges along the M6 between junction 35 at Carnforth and junction 40 at Penrith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highways England project manager Mark Mosley said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is routine work to improve maintenance access at the bridges which will in turn cause less disruption to drivers’ journeys when we need to do repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;While we will need to close the A66 overnight, work on the M6 bridges will not affect motorway journeys – although we do appreciate drivers like to know what work is going on. Local roads over the M6 will be subject to closures or temporary traffic lights and we’d advise those drivers, as well as people using the A66, to leave a little bit of extra time for journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work at Kentigern Bridge, which carries the A66 over the River Derwent, will require full closures of both the westbound and eastbound carriageways – between Crosthwaite roundabout and the junction with High Hill – for 3 nights, the dates of which have yet to be finalised but will be publicised in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work, which starts on Monday (28 November) and is due to be completed by Thursday 22 December, will mainly be done between 7am and 6pm each day using temporary traffic lights - staffed at peak times to minimise needless queuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work at Greenrigg Bridge, between junction 39 at Shap and junction 40 at Penrith, will also take place between 28 November and 22 December between 7am and 6pm each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on the 3 other M6 motorway bridges – Moss End Lane just south of junction 36 for Kirkby Lonsdale and Lupton and Hoghouse bridges between junction 36 and junction 37 for Kendal - will be done in the new year between Monday 9 January and Sunday 5 February, again between 7am and 6pm each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closure of local roads over the motorway will be accompanied by clearly-signed diversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="general-enquiries"&gt;General enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public should contact the Highways England customer contact centre on 0300 123 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="media-enquiries"&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists should contact the Highways England press office on 0844 693 1448 and use the menu to speak to the most appropriate press officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344768</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T13:27:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T13:27:03+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/major-resurfacing-work-to-take-place-on-the-a1"/>
    <title>Press release: Major resurfacing work to take place on the A1</title>
    <category label="Press release" term="Press release"/>
    <summary>Drivers are being advised that the northbound A1 in North Yorkshire will be closed this weekend as part of the A1 Leeming to Barton major road scheme. </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The A1 will be closed northbound from 8pm on Saturday 26 November until 6am on Monday 27 November between junction 50 (Leeming Bar) and Catterick North.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contractors working on behalf of Highways England will be laying more than 1,100 tonnes of new road surface as they reconstruct the northbound carriageway. The southbound carriageway will remain open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northbound traffic will be directed off the A1 at junction 49 and will re-join at junction 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The £380 million Highways England project, which began in 2014, will replace the existing dual carriageway with a new three lane motorway which will open next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="image embedded"&gt;
  &lt;div class="img"&gt;&lt;img alt="A1_image" src="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/image_data/file/58471/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highways England project manager Tom Howard said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our contractors will be replacing the existing carriageway with a new road surface which is why it is essential we close this section of the A1.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We are advising people to plan their journeys, and would like to thank drivers for their patience.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;When the whole project is complete, the section of the A1 between Leeming and Barton will be upgraded to a three-lane motorway, tackling congestion and improving journey times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drivers who intend to travel northbound on the A1 during the closure are being advised to check the &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.trafficengland.com/"&gt;latest traffic conditions&lt;/a&gt; before they set off. Clearly signed diversions will be in place and drivers are advised to allow for an extra 30 minutes to their journey time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once completed, the A1 Leeming to Barton scheme will create a continuous motorway-standard route between London and Newcastle (including the M1 and A1M). It will also improve journey times and increase safety.
For more details, &lt;a rel="external" href="http://roads.highways.gov.uk/projects/a1-leeming-to-barton-improvement/"&gt;visit the scheme website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="general-enquiries"&gt;General enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the public should contact the Highways England customer contact centre on 0300 123 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="media-enquiries"&gt;Media enquiries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists should contact the Highways England press office on 0844 693 1448 and use the menu to speak to the most appropriate press officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344771</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T13:16:08+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T13:16:08+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/mark-garniers-speech-at-the-abi-conference"/>
    <title>Speech: Mark Garnier’s speech at the ABI conference</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Speech delivered by Mark Garnier, Parliamentary Under Secretary of State at DIT, at the Association of British Insurers (ABI) conference.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many thanks for your warm reception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gives me great pleasure to address your annual conference today to such an esteemed audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Represented here today are the many facets of the insurance industry: from life and pensions through to non-life and specialty insurers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is testament to the industry’s strength and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done a huge amount of work over the last 6 years in Parliament with the finance sector, particularly with my work on the Treasury Select Committee and Parliamentary Commission on Banking Standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now delighted to have responsibility for financial services within my department, and to be addressing an absolutely vital constituent of financial services in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government enjoys a successful working relationship with the insurance industry, and has worked collaboratively with the &lt;abbr title="Association of British Insurers"&gt;ABI&lt;/abbr&gt; and others to deliver a number of key government priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example it is fantastic to see the enthusiasm and commitment from those in the industry who have committed to working with government to make the pensions dashboard a reality by 2019, helping people take control of what they decide to do with their savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you will be aware, last week the Ministry of Justice published its &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/reforming-the-soft-tissue-injury-whiplash-claims-process"&gt;consultation&lt;/a&gt; on a package of measures to tackle the high number and cost of whiplash claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package builds on previous reforms to cut costs and strengthen the medical evidence provided for such claims, and we expect them to save around £1 billion from the cost of providing motor insurance, on average around £40 per policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re pleased that some insurers have already committed to pass on 100% of the savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultation will close on 6 January 2017 and we look forward to hearing your views on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to speak about 3 main things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Firstly, an update on the changes to the machinery of government, the role of the Department for International Trade (&lt;abbr title="Department for International Trade"&gt;DIT&lt;/abbr&gt;), triggering Article 50 and exit negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Secondly, the importance of financial services, particularly in regards to the insurance industry in its own right and its value to the UK and global commerce.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thirdly, and perhaps most importantly, how we as government can work with the insurance industry to promote the work of the UK abroad, and ensure that we remain a hub of competitiveness and innovation at home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let me deal with the machinery of government changes and the role of my department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Prime Minister, Theresa May, has changed the shape of government to deal with the choice of the British people to leave the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Departments for Business and Energy and Climate Change have merged to form the Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department links industry to government to bring industrial strategy to the heart of government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department for Exiting the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; has been created to establish our new relationship with European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK is leaving the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt;, but not leaving Europe, and the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; and its members will continue to be an important trading partner for this country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it is important for us to have a successful &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; on our doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are our friends, our allies, and our nearest and biggest trading partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their success is in our best interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; will allow us to shape our own ambitious trade and investment opportunities, drive even greater openness with our partners, in Europe and beyond and put Britain firmly at the forefront of global trade and investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we do so, there will be a number of challenges that we will have to face up to and tackle head on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the message to UK businesses and global investors remains the same as it always has: the UK is a beacon for open trade and we will continue to be a bold, outward-looking nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;abbr title="Department for International Trade"&gt;DIT&lt;/abbr&gt; has been elevated to Cabinet to enhance the promotion of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department is the sales force of the country going around the world promoting Britain as a great place to invest, a great place do business, and a great place to buy our goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also the face of government to business: to gather feedback, understand your issues and listen to what is required for an effective Brexit that works for Britain and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having overall responsibility for promoting British trade across the world, we are perfectly placed to bring together government, industry and our extensive overseas network of diplomatic missions to help UK businesses grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In talking to UK businesses we want to understand what more we might do to help companies that are only currently domestically focused, look abroad for their growth opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are areas where we welcome the input of the insurance industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognise a comprehensive UK strategy needs to reflect our comparative advantage in financial and professional services alongside the traditional focus on goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The insurance industry is long used to operating in foreign markets across the globe, your knowledge and expertise in overseas markets, particularly in regard to regulatory barriers, is second to none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must work together to tackle foreign ownership restrictions, compulsory reinsurance cessions, collateral requirements, and to enable the movement of skilled people to and from overseas markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to briefly address the article 50 ruling and exit negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is disappointed by the High Court’s judgment on the proper process for triggering Article 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country voted to leave the European Union in a referendum approved by an Act of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the government is determined to respect the result of the referendum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will appeal this judgment to the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister has set out the timetable for triggering Article 50 by the end of March 2017 and that timetable has not changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we leave the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt;, our country is embarking on a long, important negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we do now will impact our country’s future for many years and decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why we are so serious about getting the best deal possible for all the UK as we leave the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is why we are not going to provide a running commentary on every twist and turn of the negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in all our interests for the UK and the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; to work together on both our withdrawal and a new relationship and for us to be able to deliver a successful outcome through a constructive negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How we take the process forward will be a matter for discussion with the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; institutions and our European partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain has been at the forefront of the free trade-supporting countries in the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; for the last 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have the right resources in place so we can secure the best possible outcome for the UK as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department will continue to hire the brightest and best talent from within the UK and from elsewhere, in order to build a world class trade policy team that can deliver the best outcomes for the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me on to the second point, the importance of the financial services industry in its own right and its value to the broader UK and global economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.2 million people work across the UK in financial and related professional services, accounting for 11.8% of the UK’s economic output and 11% of all tax revenue - that is one in every nine pounds spent on public services, like the &lt;abbr title="National Health Service"&gt;NHS&lt;/abbr&gt;, is paid from financial services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London is a truly global financial centre, ranking number one in most, if not all recent international rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is evidenced by the UK as the world’s largest exporter of financial services in the world, where we have a staggering $72 billon trade surplus, more than all other net exporting industries combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lead the way in international banking, fund management, insurance, private equity and derivatives trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK also holds a leading position in the delivery of accounting services, legal services and management consulting, which serve as an integral part of the financial services ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel="external" href="http://www.oliverwyman.com/insights/publications/2016/oct/The-impact-of-Brexit-on-the-UK-based-Financial-Services-sector.html#.WDQ_j01DS71"&gt;Oliver Wyman report&lt;/a&gt; released last month outlines the scenarios and impact of Brexit on financial services to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government fully understands the implications of Brexit to the financial services industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to turn specifically to your industry: insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognise the important contribution that insurance makes to the UK economy and its pivotal role to being a global centre for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we also recognise why insurance is so important to the broader economy of the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing a significant proportion of our financial services professionals, over 300,000, the UK insurance and long term savings industry is the largest in Europe and the third largest in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It plays an essential part in the UK’s economic strength, managing investments of 1.9 trillion pounds, equivalent to 25% of the UK’s total net worth, and paying nearly £12 billion in taxes to the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its contribution to exports is also significant, especially in the Lloyd’s and London markets, and Insurers overseas are key contributors to the UK current account balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government also recognises why the role of insurance is so important to the broader economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an essential part of everyday life, playing a crucial role in both economic development as well as having a role in supporting wider societal ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance helps oil the engine of the economy, for example in underwriting trade through trade credit, or providing peace of mind to the public through collective insurance for a host of perils including flood, fire, and health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the economy and society as a whole benefits from the certainty insurance brings through a number of ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;protecting the public through innovative risk management techniques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;freeing up businesses and professionals from everyday risks, therefore encouraging innovation, risk taking and competition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;relieving the burden from the state and providing comfort to individuals by providing safe, effective and affordable pension savings and protections products, so people can save and plan for their futures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me to address my third point,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My department’s role is to sell Britain’s capabilities and expertise, and our insurance and risk management expertise is something we can leverage as a true strength in our future trade deals and upcoming trade negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history and experience of the insurance industry is a great asset. It has been built on a foundation of innovation and an ability to adapt to changing circumstances, technology and risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many foreign governments look to the UK as the home of insurance and are looking for help and direction as their own markets grow, and to learn from our experiences, good and bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a great chance to help shape the growth and development of key markets that will be beneficial both to those countries, and also to our own industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our world leading position in the proliferation and growth of our fintech sector will be key to cementing the UK as a leading reputation for innovation, and this is also an area we will seek to collaborate with the insurance industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less than 2 weeks ago, on the 10 November, the Chancellor Philip Hammond and Chinese Vice Premier Ma Kai concluded the eighth UK-China Economic and Financial Dialogue talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the dialogue, my department invited a number of leading Chinese insurers and asset managers to the UK to engage with and build links to our own industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They provided great insight to the needs of their market and where we can work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of both this government and industry engagement, including the involvement of the Association of British Insurers, the Chinese government has agreed to create a joint task force between China and the UK on insurance and commercial pensions, to include both countries’ regulators and industry participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The China Insurance Regulatory Commission says it is also willing to work towards increasing foreign ownership of life insurance companies conducting business in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of long-term engagement we want to enhance between government and the insurance industry and we are currently looking at what other countries this level of engagement would be beneficial, such as Japan and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insurance is a long-term business, and whilst our engagement with China and India is a long-term game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to do more with developing economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the level of under-insurance in the developing world, we have significant opportunity to engage with many other markets, from key &lt;abbr title="Association of Southeast Asian Nations"&gt;ASEAN&lt;/abbr&gt; markets such as Indonesia and Malaysia, to Latin America and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why the Foreign and Commonwealth office, The Department for International Development, Her Majesties Treasury and my department are all working across Whitehall to identify markets in need of our expertise and willing to work with us. We welcome the industries inputs into this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we must never rest on our achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are determined to continue to make Britain great – indeed greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the UK’s relationship with Brexit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will carve a new mutually beneficial relationship with Europe and a stronger relationship with the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK is committed to having the best regulation in the world which promotes a stable and efficient financial services sector and supports UK economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our objectives in government are absolutely aligned to your interests in business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we work towards negotiating Brexit and getting the best deal for the UK, we will aim to limit uncertainty surrounding businesses and industries whilst also seeking to forge new relationships and seize new opportunities globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, before politics, I worked in financial markets for 27 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally understand the scale of the potential impact leaving the &lt;abbr title="European Union"&gt;EU&lt;/abbr&gt; could have for parts of the financial and professional services industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why I am determined to listen to what the industry has to say on key issues, like access to the single market and transition planning during and immediately following the process of Brexit and Article 50 negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The British government is expanding our services to support our industry with a global focus, delivering and enabling global trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK economy is fundamentally strong, highly competitive, and open for business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should build on these strengths for a new era of outward engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We very much look forward to working with the insurance industry on this crucial agenda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344662</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T10:01:11+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T10:01:11+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-hmcts-chief-executive-takes-up-role"/>
    <title>News story: New HMCTS Chief Executive takes up role</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Susan Acland-Hood has taken up post as Chief Executive of HM Courts &amp; Tribunals Service. She also announced that Kevin Sadler will be her Deputy Chief Executive.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On starting her new role Susan said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am very pleased – and know I am very privileged – to have been appointed as Chief Executive of HMCTS. I cannot imagine a better job.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What the courts and tribunals do every day is supremely important. States without justice do not function; the rule of law is one of the things that makes us civilized, and lets us live life knowing that there are some fundamental underpinnings of fairness.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I’m starting in the Ministry of Justice at a time when we have a remarkable opportunity to make a difference. The programme of root and branch change that Ministers, the judiciary and my HMCTS predecessors have developed together is one of the boldest plans in Government. And it is a plan whose time has come. With the Treasury prepared to back it to the tune of a billion pounds, we can deliver what is probably the biggest change to the system in modern times. By building what we do around the experience of those who use the system we can make justice so much better for the millions who rely on it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I am delighted to have Kevin Sadler – who has been central to the development of the reform programme, and has led it so ably during recent months – as my Deputy CEO. His experience will be essential as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;While I intend to be mostly in ‘understanding and listening’ mode in my first few weeks, there are a couple of things that I want to be clear about from the outset. The first is that we have a great reform programme that needs delivering on, not uprooting – and my job is to keep it moving, not to start again from scratch. Secondly I’m clear that HMCTS staff are dedicated, professional, and committed to delivering a really excellent service – and my job is to lead in a way that helps them do that, including by clearing out obstacles that get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;I’ve been lucky in that I was able to visit quite a few courts and tribunals around the country before I fully took up post. From those early visits I took away a clear sense of the great work that goes on in our courts and tribunals. I saw some of the changes in action – the Digital Case System and Single Justice Procedure, for example – which powerfully brought home the real impact of reform in enabling us to move away from antiquated, paper-based systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Susan Acland-Hood is on &lt;a rel="external" href="https://twitter.com/CEOofHMCTS"&gt;Twitter @ceoofhmcts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344483</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T09:59:19+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T09:59:19+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/derailment-at-southampton"/>
    <title>News story: Derailment at Southampton</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>Charter passenger train derailment, Southampton Eastern Docks, 5 November 2016.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have undertaken a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/raibs-response-to-accident-and-incident-notification#preliminary-examination"&gt;preliminary examination&lt;/a&gt; into the circumstances surrounding this accident. Having assessed the evidence which has been gathered to date, we have decided to publish a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/raibs-response-to-accident-and-incident-notification#how-raib-selects-accidents-to-investigate"&gt;safety digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The safety digest will shortly be made available on our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344729</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T08:00:17+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T08:00:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/taxpayers-lloyds-shareholding-now-less-than-8"/>
    <title>News story: Taxpayers’ Lloyds shareholding now less than 8%</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>The government has now recovered over £17 billion of the £20.3 billion taxpayers injected into Lloyds during the financial crisis.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has made further sales of its shares in Lloyds Banking Group, reducing its remaining shareholding to less than 8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest share sales, conducted via the trading plan, mean that the government has now recovered over £17 billion of the £20.3 billion taxpayers injected into Lloyds during the financial crisis, once share sales and dividends received are accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chancellor of the Exchequer Philip Hammond said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class="last-child"&gt;Selling our shares in Lloyds Banking Group and making sure that we get back all the cash taxpayers injected into it during the financial crisis is one of my top priorities as Chancellor. So I am pleased that we have continued to reduce our stake in Lloyds, and have now recovered over £17 billion for the taxpayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A trading plan involves gradually selling shares in the market over time, in an orderly and measured way. 
The Lloyds trading plan initially ran from 17 December 2014 to 31 June 2016. The government announced on 7 October 2016 that further sales of Lloyds shares would also be made through a trading plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As required by Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) rules, Lloyds Banking Group announced today that the government’s shareholding in the bank has crossed through a one percentage point threshold. This announcement therefore notifies the market that the government has reduced its shareholding in Lloyds to below 8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All proceeds from the sales are used to reduce the national debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344726</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T06:22:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-22T06:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/address-for-uks-inaugural-commonwealth-marine-economies-programme"/>
    <title>Speech: Address for UK's Inaugural Commonwealth Marine Economies Programme</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Address for the Inauguration of the UK’s Commonwealth Marine Economies Programme: Pacific Regional Workshop, 22 November 2016.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attorney General, Members of the Diplomatic corps, representatives from 12 Commonwealth countries,   members of regional organisations and civil society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a great pleasure to host the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/commonwealth-marine-economies-programme"&gt;Commonwealth Marine Economies Programme&lt;/a&gt;. I am delighted that the first consultation in this multi-regional programme is taking place here in the Pacific. For the UK, there is no better place to understand the interconnectivity of our changing climate and our oceans than here in the large ocean states of the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my short time here, I have been made acutely aware of the close relationship between Pacific people, their cultures, and the Marine Environment.  This understanding must now translate to further actions and policies to help ensure the marine economy can develop sustainably. As an Island nation, the United Kingdom is acutely aware of the challenges. We also believe that the Commonwealth’s network of Island nations offers us all a unique platform for fostering greater connectivity on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiji’s co-hosting of the 2017 UN Oceans conference means that holding this workshop in Fiji offers us all a relevant context for this dialogue. I must also congratulate Fiji as the upcoming chair of COP23. This recent announcement is further confirmation of Fiji’s ongoing leadership on both climate change and sustainable ocean management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Bainimarama highlighted this context well at COP22 when he stated that ‘For a maritime nation like Fiji, confronting the threat to the health of our seas is just as important as confronting the threat of {climate change}. The Prime Minister alluded to the importance of action now to protect oceans for the sake of generations to come. A mission that many of you gathered here today have committed long term efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK’s commitment to addressing the interplay between oceans, climate change, and economic growth is at the centre of the CME programme’s work here in the Pacific as well as with our partners in the Indian and Caribbean oceans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the ‘Our Oceans’ conference in Washington this year, the UK officiated the Pitcairn marine reserve, one of the world’s largest reserves. The UK also joins this conversation today, not only as an external partner but as a fellow custodian of the Pacific ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many of your governments have called for a greater involvement of the UK in the Pacific. This call was heeded by the British government at the Summit of Commonwealth Leaders in November last year.  The aim of this programme is to open up UK expertise to Commonwealth SIDS. I am delighted to be joined today by the UK Centre for Environment Fisheries and Aquaculture Science, the National Oceanography centre and the world’s oldest Marine Charting Authority – the UK Hydrographic Office. This world-class expertise gives us the opportunity to enhance the fundamental data needed to better balance and direct maritime policy and economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I want to emphasise that for the UK, this workshop should be a genuine consultation. This means it must be driven by you and you need to advise clearly on what you do and do not need within the scope of the Programme. I hope your discussions help to shape a clear set of next steps around the priority areas. On this note, I want to publicly recognise the work done in related areas by the Pacific Island Forum, the Commonwealth Secretariat, SPREP, SPC,  GIZ, the governments of Australia and New Zealand, as well as civil society and universities – fantastic that we are joined by representatives from all of those today so that we can move forward in partnership. I also want to acknowledge the strong role played by EU member states on climate change, including through the work of the EU delegation in the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish all participants the best of luck over the coming days and thank all of the representatives from the UK technical agencies that have travelled from one island, to another to facilitate this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344725</id>
    <published>2016-11-21T22:57:05+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-21T22:57:05+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/we-all-want-to-counter-terrorism-in-syria-but-attacks-on-schools-and-hospitals-are-not-counter-terrorist-operations"/>
    <title>Speech: "We all want to counter terrorism in Syria, but attacks on schools and hospitals are not counter terrorist operations."</title>
    <category label="Speech" term="Speech"/>
    <summary>Statement by Ambassador Matthew Rycroft, UK Permanent Representative to the United Nations, on Syria
 </summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you Stephen and Elizabeth for your powerful briefings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Nations is working tirelessly to help millions of men, women and children in desperate need in Syria. The Syrian regime and Russia, in contrast, seem determined to increase that number, to make their suffering even worse, and to prolong this barbaric conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Stephen has spelt out, this is most clearly seen in Aleppo. Hundreds of thousands of people are enduring hell, living without the most basic supplies, living – if you can call it that – in fear of barrel bombs, shelling or worse. They have gone months, without receiving a single delivery of aid or a single box of medical supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, thanks to the UN, there are trucks full of supplies ready and waiting to go. Ready and waiting to save lives. The Syrian regime, which Russia chooses to back, is deliberately preventing this food and medicine from reaching those in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia has the power to allow the aid so desperately needed into the city, if it does not the world will hold it to account for the barbarous result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I urge the Russian Federation to persuade the Syrian regime to let the UN do its job and get aid into Aleppo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the tragedy, Mr President, is that even this won’t be enough. Not content with starving thousands of innocent civilians, the Asad regime is pummelling them with sortie after sortie of devastating airstrikes. As we’ve heard, dozens have been killed and injured in the past few days alone, including through two vile attacks on the same children’s hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth has confirmed that there are no more functioning hospitals left in Eastern Aleppo. That is the result of deliberate aerial attacks on those hospitals and is part of a systematic campaign to remove even the most basic of services left in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet Russia has said, and I quote: “the allegedly bombed ‘hospitals’ in Aleppo exist only in the imagination”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know what needs to happen. I will repeat it in this Chamber again. And I will keep doing so until I am blue in the face if it means shifting the policy of the Russian Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, stop the war crimes. Attacks on hospitals, attacks on civilians, attacks on schools, attacks on vital infrastructure. These attacks serve no military purpose. How can you justify the bombing of a school, like the one in Idlib? How can you justify the killing of 20 children and three teachers? As Elbio said, there is no God and no principle that can possibly justify such an attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all want to counter terrorism in Syria, but attacks on schools and hospitals are not counter terrorist operations. So we support Staffan de Mistura’s request to send a UN verification team to investigate the attacks on hospitals in Aleppo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, aid needs to get in. We commend the UN on their humanitarian response plan for Aleppo. All parties need to implement it fully and immediately. But this issue goes far beyond Aleppo. As Stephen said, the UN now puts the number of those living in besieged areas at almost 1 million people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aid must reach those people.  Unless we see an improvement, November will be the worst month yet for efforts to deliver aid to besieged and hard to reach areas across Syria.  Not one single humanitarian convoy has reached any of those areas on the UN’s plan this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are two simple steps. And they must be taken if we are to have a chance of that most elusive of third step; political talks that will bring an end to this horrific conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have said many times before, Russia has a unique role to play in all three of those steps. To persuade the regime to end its destructive military approach, to allow full humanitarian access to all besieged areas, and to commit to a political settlement to end this brutal war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.gov.uk,2005:AnnouncementPresenter/344722</id>
    <published>2016-11-21T20:37:55+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-21T20:37:55+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/wharton-uk-reiterates-its-commitment-to-the-drc"/>
    <title>News story: Wharton: UK reiterates its commitment to the DRC</title>
    <category label="News story" term="News story"/>
    <summary>International Development Minister James Wharton returns from the DRC where he urged timely elections for the first ever peaceful transition of power.</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="govspeak"&gt;&lt;p&gt;During his first visit to the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), the Minister emphasised the UK’s commitment to its people and stressed our continued work in partnership to build a developed, stable and prosperous DRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the capital city Kinshasa, Minister Wharton met Prime Minister Matata and Vice Prime Minister of Interior and Security Boshab.  He urged them, as part of the DRC Government, to ensure peaceful, timely and free and fair elections, following a history of violent political transitions and recent civil unrest. He also called on the Government to tackle the current economic challenges facing the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minister saw the positive impact of the UK’s investment in a power plant at Virunga Park, in Matebe, which is providing 96 megawatts of clean energy, creating around 100,000 jobs and boosting economic development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This investment is routed through CDC, the UK and the world’s oldest development finance institution. CDC is making pioneering investments in the hardest to reach markets across Africa to support local businesses, stimulate economic growth and help countries lift themselves out of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister James Wharton said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is an historic moment for DRC and an opportunity for this great country to make its first ever peaceful transition of power, building stability and security – which is firmly in DRC and the UK’s interests. All parties need to find a genuinely inclusive agreement, which is vital before elections take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have seen first-hand how the UK is providing lifesaving assistance and supporting the country to tackle poverty, stimulate economic growth and create jobs and livelihoods for the poorest people, helping them to stand on their own two feet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Goma in Eastern DRC, the Minister saw how the UK is working with local partners such as the United Nations Stabilisation Mission in the DRC (MONUSCO) to deliver life-changing support to the most vulnerable people. He met beneficiaries of a UK aid-funded urban water and sanitation programme, which is providing 150,000 people with clean water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also visited an ICRC hospital – supported by UK aid – and met war surgeons who are saving lives of those harmed by conflict, treating emergency wounds and supporting the physical rehabilitation and psychological recovery of patients, including amputees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 5 years, UK support in DRC has helped:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide 1.6 million people with sustainable access to clean water and 1.36 million people with improved sanitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide 150,000 people with emergency food assistance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve access to security and justice services for 950,000 girls and women&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable 600,000 mothers to give birth safely and 200,000 women to access family planning support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
